<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Robin H[oods] garlan[d.] Containing his merry exploits, and the several fights which he, Little John, and Will. Scarlet had, upon several occasions. Some of them never before printed. Entred according to order.</title>
            <author>Robins, Thomas, fl. 1672-1685.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1675</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 102 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 50 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A57413</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing R1640</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R219693</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99831146</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99831146</idno>
            <idno type="VID">35608</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A57413)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 35608)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 2039:31)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Robin H[oods] garlan[d.] Containing his merry exploits, and the several fights which he, Little John, and Will. Scarlet had, upon several occasions. Some of them never before printed. Entred according to order.</title>
                  <author>Robins, Thomas, fl. 1672-1685.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[96] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for F. Coles, T. [Vere, &amp; J. Wright,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London] :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1670-1680?]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Imprint from Wing.</note>
                  <note>Title page woodcut.</note>
                  <note>Contents on verso of title page.</note>
                  <note>In verse.</note>
                  <note>Signatures: A-F.</note>
                  <note>Imperfect: pages stained and torn with print show-through; title page torn and cropped, with loss of text and imprint; imprint information supplied by Wing.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Robin Hood (Legendary character) --  Poetry --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2011-02</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-02</date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-04</date>
            <label>Graham Hukill</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-04</date>
            <label>Graham Hukill</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <p>
               <pb facs="tcp:35608:1"/>
Robin H<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>Garlan<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
            </p>
            <figure/>
            <p>Containing his Merry Exploits, and the ſeveral Fights which he, <hi>Little John,</hi> and <hi>Will. Scarlet</hi> had, upon ſeveral occaſions. Some of them never before Printed.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Entred according to Order.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 line">
                  <desc>〈1 line〉</desc>
               </gap>
            </p>
            <pb facs="tcp:35608:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:35608:2"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
         </div>
         <div type="table_of_contents">
            <pb facs="tcp:35608:3"/>
            <head>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>NTENTS.</head>
            <p>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> 
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ods progreſs to <hi>Nottingham,</hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> he ſlew fifteen Forreſters.</p>
            <p>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> 
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ood newly revived, or his meeting <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> with his Couſin <hi>Scarlet.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>in <hi>Hood</hi> &amp; the jolly Pinder of <hi>Wake<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
               </hi>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> ſhewing how he fought with <hi>Rob. Hood, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap>,</hi> and <hi>Iohn,</hi> a long Summers day.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>obin Hood</hi> and the Biſhop, ſhewing how <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> robbed him, and made him ſing Maſs.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Robin Hood</hi> and the Butcher, ſhewing how he robbed the Sherriff of <hi>Nottingham.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Robin Hoods<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
               </hi> reſcuing <hi>Will Stutly</hi> from the Sheriff, which was going to hang him.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Robin Hood</hi> and the Begger, ſhewing how he reſcued three brethren that were going to be hanged for ſtealing Deer.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Robin Hood</hi> and Queen <hi>Ratherine.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Robin Hood</hi> and the Tanner, ſhewing how the Tanner was kin to little <hi>Iohn.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>A famous battel between <hi>Robin Hood</hi> and a Curtal Fryer, neer Fountain-Dale.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Robin Hoods</hi> preferment, ſhewing how he took a Ship at Sea with 12000 pound in her<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Robin Hood</hi> and the Shepherd, ſhewing how the Shepherd beat him and little <hi>Iohn.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Robin Hoods</hi> Golden prize, ſhewing how he robb'd two Prieſts of five hundred pound.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Robin Hoods</hi> Chaſe, or a merry progreſs between him and King <hi>Henry.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Little <hi>Iohn</hi> and the Four Beggers.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Robin Hoods</hi> Delight.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:35608:3"/>
            <head>ROBIN HOOD'S Garland.</head>
            <div type="part">
               <head>Robin Hood's Progreſs to Nottingham, where he ſlew Fifteen Forreſters.</head>
               <opener>To the Tune of, Bold Robin Hood.</opener>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <hi>RObin Hood</hi> he was a tall young-man,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And fifteen Winters old,</l>
                  <l>And <hi>Robin Hood</hi> he was a proper young-man</l>
                  <l>Of courage ſtout and bold:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>hey down, derry derry down.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Robin hood</hi> he would unto fair <hi>Nottingham,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>With the General for to dine,</l>
                  <l>There was he aware of fifteen Forreſters,</l>
                  <l>And a drinking Beer, Ale, and Wine:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>hey down, derry, derry, down.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>What news? what news? ſaid bold <hi>Rob. Hood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry, derry, down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>What news fain wouldſt thou know?</l>
                  <l>Our King hath p<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ovided a Shooting match,</l>
                  <l>And i'm ready with my Bow:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>hey down,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>We hold it in ſcorn, then ſaid the Forreſters,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:4"/>
                  <l>That ever a Boy ſo young,</l>
                  <l>Should bear a Bow before our King,</l>
                  <l>That's not able to draw one ſtring:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>hey down,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>I'le hold you 20 mark, ſiad bold <hi>Robin Hood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>By the leave of our Lady,</l>
                  <l>That i'le hit a Mark a hundred Rod,</l>
                  <l>And i'le cauſe a Hart to dye:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>hey down,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>We'l hold you 20 Mark, then ſaid the Forre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſters,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>By the leave of our Lady,</l>
                  <l>Thou hit'ſt not the Mark an hundred Rod,</l>
                  <l>Nor cauſeſt an Hart to dye:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>hey down,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Robin Hood</hi> he bent up a Noble Bow,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And a Broad Arrow he let flye,</l>
                  <l>He hit the Mark an hundred Rod,</l>
                  <l>And he cauſed an Hart to dye<hi>:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>hey down,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Some ſaid he brake Ribs one or two,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And ſome ſaid he brake three,</l>
                  <l>The Arrow in the Hart would not abide,</l>
                  <l>But it glanced in two or three:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>hey down, derry, derry, down.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:4"/>
                  <l>The Hart did skip, and the Hart did leap,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry, derry down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And the Hart lay on the ground,</l>
                  <l>The Wager is mine, ſaid bold <hi>Robin Hood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>If it were for a thouſand pound:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>hey down, derry, derry, down.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The Wager's none of thine, then ſaid the Forreſters,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry, derry, down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Although thou be'ſt in haſte,</l>
                  <l>Take up thy Bow and get thee hence,</l>
                  <l>Leſt we thy ſides do baſte:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>hey down,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Robin Hood</hi> he took up his Noble Bow,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry, derry, down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And his Broad Arrows all amain,</l>
                  <l>And <hi>Robin</hi> he laught and began to ſmile,</l>
                  <l>As he went over the plain:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>hey down,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then <hi>Robin Hood</hi> he bent his Noble Bow,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry, derry, down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And his Broad Arrows he let flye,</l>
                  <l>Till fourteen of theſe fifteen Forreſters</l>
                  <l>Vpon the ground did lye:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>hey down,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>He that did this quarrel firſt begin,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry, derry, down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Went tripping over the Plain,</l>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:5"/>
                  <l>But <hi>Robin Hood</hi> he bent his Noble Bow,</l>
                  <l>And he fetcht him back again:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>hey down,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>You ſaid I was no archer, ſaid bold <hi>Ro. hood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>But ſay ſo now again,</l>
                  <l>With that he ſent another arrow,</l>
                  <l>Which ſplit his head in twain:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>hey down,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>You have found me an archer, ſaid <hi>Ro. Hood<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                     </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Which will make your Wives for to wring,</l>
                  <l>And wiſh that you had never ſpoke the word,</l>
                  <l>That I could not draw one ſtring:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>hey down,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The People that lived in fair <hi>Nottingham,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Came running out amain,</l>
                  <l>Suppoſing to have taken bold <hi>Robin hood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>With the Forreſters that were ſlain:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>hey down,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Some loſt Legs, and ſome loſt arms,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And ſome did loſe their blood,</l>
                  <l>But <hi>Robin hood</hi> he took up his Noble Bow</l>
                  <l>And is gone to the merry green-wood:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>hey down,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:5"/>
                  <l>They carried theſe forreſters to fair <hi>Notting<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ham,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>As many there did know,</l>
                  <l>They dig'd them Graves in their Church<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>yard,</l>
                  <l>And they buried them all on a row:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>hey down, derry derry down.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>Robin Hood <hi>newly Revived: Or, His Meeting and Fighting with his Couſin Scarlet.</hi>
               </head>
               <opener>To a delightful new Tune.</opener>
               <lg>
                  <l>COme liſten a while you Gentlemen all,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey down down a down down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>That are in this Bower within:</l>
                  <l>for a ſtory of gailant <hi>Robin Hood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>I purpoſe now to begin.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>What time of the day, qd. <hi>Robin hood</hi> then,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Quoth little <hi>John,</hi> 'tis in the prime,</l>
                  <l>why then we will to the green-wood gang,</l>
                  <l>For we have no Victuals to dine.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>As <hi>Robin hood</hi> walkt the Forreſt along,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>It was in the midſt of the day,</l>
                  <l>there was he ware of a deft young-man,</l>
                  <l>As ever walkt on the way.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>His Doublet it was of ſilk, he ſaid,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:6"/>
                  <l>His Stockings like Scarlet ſhone,</l>
                  <l>and he walkt on along the way,</l>
                  <l>To <hi>Robin Hood</hi> then unknown.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>A Herd of Deer was in the Bend,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>All feeding before his face,</l>
                  <l>now the beſt of you i'le have for my Dinner,</l>
                  <l>And that in a little ſpace.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Now the Stranger made no mickle ado,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>But he bends and a right good Bow,</l>
                  <l>and the beſt Buck in the Herd he ſlew,</l>
                  <l>Forty yards him full fro.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Well ſhot, well ſhot, quoth <hi>Robin hood</hi> then,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>That ſhot it was in time,</l>
                  <l>and if thou wilt accept of the place,</l>
                  <l>Thou ſhalt be a bold Yeoman of mine.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Go play the Chiven, the Stranger ſaid,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Make haſte and quickly go,</l>
                  <l>or with my fiſt, be ſure of this,</l>
                  <l>I'le give thee buffets ſtore.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Thou hadſt not beſt buffet me, qd. <hi>Robin hood</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:6"/>
                  <l>For although I am forlorn,</l>
                  <l>yet I have thoſe will take my part,</l>
                  <l>If I but blow my Horn.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Thou waſt not beſt wind thy horn the ſtranger ſaid,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Beeſt thou never ſo much in haſte,</l>
                  <l>for I can draw a good broad Sword,</l>
                  <l>And quickly cut the blaſt.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then <hi>Robin hood</hi> he bent a very good Bow,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>To ſhoot, and that he would fain,</l>
                  <l>the ſtranger he bent a very good Bow,</l>
                  <l>To ſhoot at bold <hi>Robin</hi> again.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>O hold thy hand, hold thy hand, qd. <hi>Ro. hood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>To ſhoot it would be in vain, for if we ſhould ſhoot the one at the other,</l>
                  <l>The one of us muſt be ſlain.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But let's take our ſwords and our broad Buck<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lers,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>hey down,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>And gang under yonder Tree,</l>
                  <l>as I hope to be ſav'd, the ſtranger he ſaid,</l>
                  <l>One foot I will not flee.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then <hi>Robin hood</hi> lent the ſtranger a blow,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Moſt ſcar'd him out of his wit,</l>
                  <l>thou never felt blow, the ſtranger he ſaid,</l>
                  <l>That ſhall be better quit.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:7"/>
                  <l>The ſtranger he drew out a good broad ſword,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>And hit <hi>Robin</hi> on the crown,</l>
                  <l>that from every hair of bold <hi>Robins</hi> head,</l>
                  <l>The blood ran trickling down.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>God a mercy good fellow, qd. <hi>Rob. hood</hi> then,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>And for this thou haſt done,</l>
                  <l>tell me good fellow what thou art,</l>
                  <l>Tell me where thou doſt woon.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The ſtranger then anſwered bold <hi>Rob. hood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>I'le tell thee where I did dwell,</l>
                  <l>in <hi>Maxfield</hi> was I bred and born,</l>
                  <l>My name is young <hi>Gamwel.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>For killing of my Fathers Steward,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>I am fore'd to this Engliſh Wood,</l>
                  <l>and for to ſeek an Vncle of mine,</l>
                  <l>Some call him <hi>Robin hood.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But art thou a Couſin of <hi>Robin hoods</hi> then?</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>The ſooner we ſhould have done,</l>
                  <l>as I hope to be ſav'd, the ſtranger then ſaid,</l>
                  <l>I am his own Siſters Son.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:7"/>
                  <l>But Lord what a kiſſing and courting was there,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hoy, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>When theſe two Couſins did greet,</l>
                  <l>and they went all that Summers day,</l>
                  <l>And little <hi>Iohn</hi> did meet.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But when they met with little <hi>Iohn,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>He there unto him did ſay,</l>
                  <l>O Maſter where have you been,</l>
                  <l>You have tarried ſo long away?</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>I met with a ſtranger, qd. <hi>Robin hood</hi> then,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Full ſore he hath beaten me,</l>
                  <l>then i'le have about with him, qd. little <hi>Iohn,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And try if he can beat me.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Oh no, oh no, quoth <hi>Robin hood</hi> then,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Little <hi>Iohn</hi> it may not be ſo:</l>
                  <l>for he's my own dear Siſters Son,</l>
                  <l>And Couſins I have no mo.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But he ſhall be a bold Yeoman of mine,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>My chief man next to thee:</l>
                  <l>and I <hi>Robin hood,</hi> and thou little <hi>Iohn,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And <hi>Scarlet</hi> he ſhall be.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:8"/>
                  <l>And we'l be three of the braveſt Out-laws,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>That is in the North-Country,</l>
                  <l>if thou wilt have any more of bold <hi>Ro. hood</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>In the ſecond part it will be.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then bold <hi>Robin hood</hi> to the North he would go,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>With valour and mickle might,</l>
                  <l>with Sword by his ſide, which oft had been try'd,</l>
                  <l>To fight and recover his right.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The firſt that he met was a bonny bold <hi>Scot,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>His ſervant he ſaid he would be,</l>
                  <l>no, quoth <hi>Robin hood,</hi> it cannot be good,</l>
                  <l>For thou wilt prove falſe unto me.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Thou haſt not been true to Sire nor Cuz,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Nay, marry the <hi>Scot</hi> he ſaid,</l>
                  <l>as true as your heart, i'le never part,</l>
                  <l>Gude Maſter be not afraid.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then <hi>Robin hood</hi> turn'd his face to the Eaſt,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Fight on my merry men ſtout,</l>
                  <l>our caſe is good, qd. brave <hi>Robin hood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And we ſhall not be beaten out.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:8"/>
                  <l>The Battel grows hot on every ſide,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>The <hi>Scothman</hi> made great moan,</l>
                  <l>qd. <hi>Jocky,</hi> gude faith they fight on each ſide</l>
                  <l>Would I were with my Wife <hi>Joan.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The Enemy compaſt brave <hi>Robin</hi> about,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>'Tis long e're the Battel ends,</l>
                  <l>there's neither will yield, nor give up the field,</l>
                  <l>For both are ſupply'd with friends.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>This ſong it was made in <hi>Robin hoods</hi> days,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Let's pray unto <hi>jove</hi> above,</l>
                  <l>to give us true peace, that miſchief may ceaſe</l>
                  <l>And War may give place unto love.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>Robin Hood <hi>and the jolly Pinder of</hi> Wake-field, <hi>ſhewing how he fought with</hi> Robin Hood, Scarlet, and John, <hi>a long Summers day.</hi>
               </head>
               <opener>To a Northern Tune.</opener>
               <lg>
                  <l>IN <hi>Wakefield</hi> there lives a jolly Pinder,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>in Wakefield all on a Green,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>in Wakefield all on a Green,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>There's neither Knight nor Squire, ſaid the Pinder,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>nor Barron that is ſo bold,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>nor Barron that is ſo bold.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:9"/>
                  <l>Dare make a treſpaſs to the town of <hi>Wake<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>field,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l> but his Pledge goes to the Pinfold,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>but his Pledge goes to the Pinfold.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>All this beheard three witty young-men,</l>
                  <l>'twas <hi>Robin Hood, Scarlet,</hi> and <hi>Iohn, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>With that they ſpyed the jolly Pinder,</l>
                  <l>as he ſat under a Thorn, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Now turn again, turn again, ſaid the Pinder,</l>
                  <l>for a wrong way have you gone, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>For you have forſaken the Kings High-way,</l>
                  <l>and made a path over the Corn, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>O that were great ſhame, ſaid jolly <hi>Robin,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>we being three, and thou but one, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>The Pinder leapt back then thirty good foot,</l>
                  <l>'twas thirty good foot and one, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>He leaned his back faſt unto a Thorn,</l>
                  <l>and his foot againſt a Stone, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And there he fought a long Summers day,</l>
                  <l>and a Summers day ſo long, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Till their Swords on their broad bucklers,</l>
                  <l>were broken faſt unto their hands, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Hold thy hand, hold thy hand (ſaid <hi>Rob. hood)</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>and my merry men every one, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For this is one of the beſt Pinders</l>
                  <l>that ever I try'd with ſword, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:9"/>
                  <l>And wilt thou forſake the Pinder his craft,</l>
                  <l>and live in green-wood with me, &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>At <hi>Michaelmas</hi> next my Covenant comes out</l>
                  <l>when every man gathers his fee, &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Ile take my blew blade in my hand,</l>
                  <l>and plod to the green-wood with thee, &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Haſt either meat or drink, ſaid <hi>Robin hood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l> for my meery men and me, &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>I have both bread and beef, ſaid the Pinder,</l>
                  <l>and good Ale of the beſt, &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>And that's meat good enough, ſaid <hi>Ro. hood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>for ſuch unbidden gueſt, &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>O wilt thou forſake the Pinder his craft,</l>
                  <l>and go to the green-wood with me, &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Thou ſhalt have a Livery twice in the year,</l>
                  <l>the one green, the other brown, &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>If <hi>Michaelmas</hi> day were once come and gone,</l>
                  <l>and my Maſter had paid me my fee, &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Then would I <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>et as little by him,</l>
                  <l>as my Maſter doth by me,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>as my Maſter doth by me.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <pb facs="tcp:35608:10"/>
               <head>Robin Hood <hi>and the Biſhop Shewing how</hi> Robin Hood <hi>went to an Old Womans houſe, and changed Cloaths with her to ſcape from the Biſhop, and how he rob'd the Biſhop of all his Gold, and made him ſing a Maſs.</hi>
               </head>
               <opener>To the Tune of, Robin Hood and the Stranger.</opener>
               <lg>
                  <l>COme Gentlemen all, and liſten a while,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey down down an a down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And a Story i'le to you unfold;</l>
                  <l>i'le tell you how <hi>Robin Hood</hi> ſerv'd the Biſhop,</l>
                  <l>When he rob'd him of his Gold.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>As it fell out on a Sun ſhining day,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>When <hi>Phoebus</hi> was in his prime,</l>
                  <l>then <hi>Robin Hood,</hi> that <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap>cher good,</l>
                  <l>In mirth would ſpend ſome time.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>As he walked the Forreſt along,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> 
                     <g ref="char:punc">▪</g>c.</l>
                  <l>Some paſtime for to ſpy,</l>
                  <l>there was he aware of a proud Biſhop,</l>
                  <l>And all his company.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>O what ſhall I do, ſaid <hi>Robin hood</hi> then?</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>If the Biſhop he doth take me,</l>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:10"/>
                  <l>no mercy he'l ſhow, unto me I know.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then <hi>Robin</hi> was ſtout, and turn'd him about,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>And a little houſe there he did ſpy,</l>
                  <l>And to an old Wife to ſave his life,</l>
                  <l>He loud began to cry.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Why who art thou, ſaid the old Woman,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Come tell it to me for good,</l>
                  <l>I am an Out-law, as many do know,</l>
                  <l>My name it is <hi>Robin Hood.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>And yonder's the Biſhop and all his Men,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>And if that I taken be,</l>
                  <l>Then day and night, he'l work me ſpight,</l>
                  <l>And hanged I ſhall be.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>If thou be <hi>Robin Hood,</hi> ſaid the old Wife,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>As thou doſt ſeem to be,</l>
                  <l>I'le for thee provide, and thee I will hide</l>
                  <l>From the Biſhop and his Company.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>For I well remember on Saturday-night,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:11"/>
                  <l>Thou bought me both ſhooes and hoſe,</l>
                  <l>Therefore i'le provide, thy perſon to hide,</l>
                  <l>and keep thee from thy foes.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then give me ſoon thy Coat of Gray,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>And take thou my Mantle of Green,</l>
                  <l>Thy Spindle and Twine, unto me reſign,</l>
                  <l>and take thou my Arrows ſo keen.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>And when that <hi>Robin hood</hi> was ſo array'd,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>He went ſtraight to his company,</l>
                  <l>With his Spindle and Twine, he oft loo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> behin<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>for the Biſhop and his company.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>O who is yonder, quoth little <hi>Iohn,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>That now comes over the Lee,</l>
                  <l>An Arrow I will at her let flye,</l>
                  <l>ſo like an old Witch looks ſhe.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>O hold thy hand, hold thy hand, ſaid Rob<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap> the</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>And ſhoot not thy Arrows ſo keen,</l>
                  <l>I am <hi>Robin hood,</hi> thy Maſter good,</l>
                  <l>and quickly it ſhall be ſeen.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The Biſhop he came to the old Womans</l>
                  <l>hou<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap> 
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:11"/>
                  <l>And he called with furious mood,</l>
                  <l>Come let me ſoon ſee, and bring unto me</l>
                  <l>that traytor <hi>Robin Hood.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The old woman he ſet on a milk-white ſteed,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Himſelf on a Dapple Gray,</l>
                  <l>And for joy he had got <hi>Robin Hood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>he went laughing all the way.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But as they were riding the Forreſt along,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>The Biſhop he chanced to ſee,</l>
                  <l>A hundred bra<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>e Bow-men bold,</l>
                  <l>ſtand under the Green-wood-tree.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>O who is yonder? the Biſhop he ſaid,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>That's ranging within yonder wood<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                  </l>
                  <l>Marry, ſays the old woman, I think it to be,</l>
                  <l>a Man called <hi>Robin Hood.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Why who art thou, the Biſhop he ſaid?</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Which I have here with me,</l>
                  <l>Why I am an old Woman, thou Cuckold<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>g Biſhop<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                  </l>
                  <l>lift up my Leg and ſee.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then woe to me, the Biſhop he ſaid,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:12"/>
                  <l>That ever I ſaw this day:</l>
                  <l>He turn'd him about, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ut <hi>Robin hood</hi> ſo ſtout</l>
                  <l>call'd to him and bid him ſtay.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then <hi>Robin</hi> took hold of the Biſhops horſe,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And ty'd him faſt to a tree,</l>
                  <l>Then Little <hi>Iohn</hi> ſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap>iſed his Maſter upon,</l>
                  <l>for joy of that company.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Robin Hood</hi> took his Mantle from's back,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>And ſpread it upon the ground.</l>
                  <l>And out of the Biſhops Portmantle, he</l>
                  <l>ſoon told five hundred pound.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>So now <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>et him go, ſaid <hi>Robin Hood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Said little <hi>Iohn</hi> that may not <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>e;</l>
                  <l>For I vow and prote<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap>, he ſhall ſing as a Maſs</l>
                  <l>before that he go from me.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then <hi>Robin Hood</hi> took the Biſhop by the hand</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>And bound him faſt to a tree,</l>
                  <l>And made him ſing a Maſs God-wot,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap> him and his Yeoman-dree.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>And then they brought him through the wood,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:12"/>
                  <l>And ſet him on his Dapple Gray,</l>
                  <l>And gave the tayl within his hand,</l>
                  <l>and bid him for <hi>Robin Hood</hi> pray.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>Robin Hood <hi>and the Butcher. Shewing how he robbed the Sherriff of</hi> Not<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tingham.</head>
               <opener>
                  <hi>Tune of,</hi> Robin Hood and the Beggar.</opener>
               <lg>
                  <l>COme all ye brave gallants, &amp; liſten a while</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey down, down, an a down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l> that are in this Bower within,</l>
                  <l>For of <hi>Robin Hood,</hi> that Archer good,</l>
                  <l>a Song I intend to ſing.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Vpon a time it chanced ſo,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>bold <hi>Robin</hi> in the Forreſt did ſpy,</l>
                  <l>A jolly Butcher, with a bonny fine Mare,</l>
                  <l>with his fleſh to the Market did hye.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Good morrow, good fellow, ſaid jolly Robin,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>what food haſt, tell unto me,</l>
                  <l>And thy trade to me tell, and where thou doſt dweſt,</l>
                  <l>for I like well thy company.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The Butcher he anſwered jolly Robin,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:13"/>
                  <l>no matter where I dwell,</l>
                  <l>For a Butcher I am, and to <hi>Nottingham,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l> I am going my fleſh to ſell.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>What's the price of thy fleſh, ſaid jolly <hi>Robin,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>come tell it ſoon unto me,</l>
                  <l>And the price of my Mare, be ſhe never ſo dear</l>
                  <l>for a Butcher fain would I be.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The price of my fleſh, the Butcher reply'd,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>I ſoon will tell unto thee,</l>
                  <l>With my bonny Mare, &amp; they are not dear,</l>
                  <l>four Mark thou muſt give unto me.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Four Mark I will give thee, ſaid jolly <hi>Robin,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>four Mark it ſhall be thy Fee,</l>
                  <l>Thy money come count, and let me mount,</l>
                  <l>for a Butcher I fain would be.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Now <hi>Robin</hi> he is to <hi>Nottingham</hi> gone,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>his Butchers trade for to begin,</l>
                  <l>With a good intent, to the Sheriff he went,</l>
                  <l>and there he took up his Inn.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>When other Butchers did open their ſhop,
<pb facs="tcp:35608:13"/>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>bold <hi>Robin</hi> he then begun;</l>
                  <l>But how for to ſell, he knew not well,</l>
                  <l>for a butcher he was but young.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>When other butchers no meat could ſell,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Robin</hi> got both Gold and Fee,</l>
                  <l>For he ſold more meat for one Penny,</l>
                  <l>than others could do for three.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But when he ſold his Meat ſo faſt,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>no butcher by him could thrive,</l>
                  <l>For he ſold more meat for one penny,</l>
                  <l>than others could do for five.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Which made the butchers of <hi>Nottingham,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>to ſtudy as they did ſtand,</l>
                  <l>Saying, ſurely he was ſome Prodigal,</l>
                  <l>that had ſold his Fathers Land.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The butchers they ſtepped to jolly <hi>Robin,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>acquainted with him for to be,</l>
                  <l>Come brother, one ſaid, we be all of one trade<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                  </l>
                  <l>come will you go dine with me?</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:14"/>
                  <l>Accurſt of his heart, ſaid jolly <hi>Robin,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>That a Butcher will deny:</l>
                  <l>I will go with you my Brethren true,</l>
                  <l>and as faſt as I can hye.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But when to the Sheriffs houſe they came,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>to Dinner they hyed apace,</l>
                  <l>And <hi>Robin</hi> he the man muſt be,</l>
                  <l>before them all to ſay Grace.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Pray God bleſs us all, ſaid jolly <hi>Robin,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>and our Meat within this place,</l>
                  <l>A cup of Sack ſo good, will nouriſh our blood,</l>
                  <l>and ſo I end my Grace.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Come fill us more Wine, ſaid jolly <hi>Robin,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>let us be merry while we do ſtay,</l>
                  <l>For Wine and good chear, be it never ſo dear</l>
                  <l>I vow I the reckoning will pay.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Come Brothers be merry, ſaid jolly <hi>Robin,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>let us drink and never give o're,</l>
                  <l>For the ſhot I will pay, e're I go my way,</l>
                  <l>if it coſt me five pound or more.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:14"/>
                  <l>This is a mad blade, the Butchers then ſaid,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>ſays the Sherriff, he is ſome Prodigal,</l>
                  <l>That ſome Land has ſold, for ſilver and gold,</l>
                  <l>and now he doth mean to ſpend all.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Haſt thou any horn'd Beaſts, the Sheriff then ſaid,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>good fellow, to ſell unto me:</l>
                  <l>Yes that I have, good Maſter Sheriff,</l>
                  <l>I have hundreds two or three.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>A hundred Akers of good free Land,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>if you pleaſe it to ſee,</l>
                  <l>And i'le make you as good aſſurance of it</l>
                  <l>as ever my Father made me.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The Sheriff he ſadled a good Palfrey,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>And with three hundred pound in Gold,</l>
                  <l>Away he went with bold <hi>Robin Hood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l> his horned-beaſts to behold.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Away then the Sheriff and <hi>Robin</hi> did rids,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>to the Forreſt of merry <hi>Sherwood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Then the Sheriff did ſay, God bleſs us this day,</l>
                  <l>from a man they call <hi>Robin Hood.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:15"/>
                  <l>But when that a little further they came,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>bold <hi>Robin</hi> he chanced to ſpy,</l>
                  <l>A hundred Head of good Red Deer,</l>
                  <l>come tripping the Sheriff full nigh.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>How like you my Horn'd-beaſts, good Maſter Sheriff,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>they be fat and fair for to ſee,</l>
                  <l>I tell thee good fellow, I would I were gone,</l>
                  <l>for I like not thy company.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then <hi>Robin</hi> he ſet his Horn to his mouth,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>and blew but blaſts three,</l>
                  <l>Then quickly anon, there came little <hi>Iohn,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>and all his company.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>What is your will maſter, ſaid Little <hi>Iohn,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>I pray you come tell it to me,</l>
                  <l>I have brought hither the Sheriff of <hi>Notting<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ham.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>this day to dine with thee.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>He is welcome to me, then ſaid little <hi>Iohn,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>I hope he will honeſtly pay;</l>
                  <l>I know he has gold, if it were but well told,</l>
                  <l>will ſerve us to drink a whole day.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:15"/>
                  <l>Then <hi>Robin</hi> took his mantle from his back,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>and laid it upon the ground:</l>
                  <l>And out of the Sheriffs Portmantle,</l>
                  <l>he told three hundred pound.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then <hi>Robin</hi> brought him thorow the wood,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey down down an a down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>and ſet him on his dapple grey:</l>
                  <l>O have me commended to your wife at home,</l>
                  <l>ſo <hi>Robin</hi> went laughing away.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>Robin Hood <hi>his reſcuing</hi> Will Stutly <hi>from the Sheriff and his Men, who had taken him Priſoner, and were going to hang him.</hi>
               </head>
               <opener>
                  <hi>To the Tune of,</hi> Robin Hood and Queen <hi>Katherine.</hi>
               </opener>
               <lg>
                  <l>WHen <hi>Robin hood</hi> in the green wood liv'd,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Vnder the green-wood-tree;</l>
                  <l>Tydings there came to him with ſpeed,</l>
                  <l>Tydings for certainty,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>hey down, derry derry down.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>That <hi>Will Sutly</hi> ſurprized was,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And eke in Priſon lay,</l>
                  <l>Three Varlets that the Sheriff had hired,</l>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:16"/>
                  <l>Did likely him betray.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>I, and to morrow hang'd muſt be,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>To morrow as ſoon as it is day,</l>
                  <l>But before they could this victory get,</l>
                  <l>Two of them did <hi>Stutly</hi> ſlay.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>When <hi>Robin Hood</hi> he heard this News,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Lord he was grieved ſore,</l>
                  <l>I and unto his merry men ſaid,</l>
                  <l>(Who altogether ſwore)</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>That <hi>Will Stutly</hi> ſhould reſcued be,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry, derry, down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And be brought ſafe again,</l>
                  <l>Or elſe ſhould many a gallant wight</l>
                  <l>For his ſake there he ſlain.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>He cloathed himſelf in Scarlet then,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry, derry, down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>His men were all in green,</l>
                  <l>A fairer ſhew throughout the World,</l>
                  <l>In no part could be ſeen.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Good Lord it was a gallant ſight,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>To ſee them all on a row,</l>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:16"/>
                  <l>With every man a good broad Sword,</l>
                  <l>And eke a good Yew Bow.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Forth of the green-wood are they gone,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Yea all couragiouſly,</l>
                  <l>Reſolving to bring <hi>Stutly</hi> home,</l>
                  <l>Or every man to dye.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>And when they came the Caſtle neer,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Whereas <hi>Will Stutly</hi> lay:</l>
                  <l>I hold it good, ſays <hi>Robin Hood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>We here in ambuſh ſtay.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>And ſend one forth ſome news to hear,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>To yonder Palmer fair,</l>
                  <l>That ſtands under the Caſtle-wall,</l>
                  <l>Some news he may declare.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>With that ſteps forth a brave young-man,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Which was of courage bold,</l>
                  <l>Thus he did to the old man ſay,</l>
                  <l>I pray thee Palmer old.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Tell me if that thou rightly <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>en,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:17"/>
                  <l>When muſt <hi>Will Stutly</hi> dye?</l>
                  <l>Who is one of bold Robin <hi>hoods</hi> men,</l>
                  <l>And here doth Priſoner lye.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Alas, alas, the Palmer ſaid,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And for ever woe is me,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Will Stutly</hi> hanged muſt be this day,</l>
                  <l>On yonder Gallows-tree.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>O had his noble Maſter known,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>He would ſome ſuccour ſend,</l>
                  <l>A few of his bold Yeomandree,</l>
                  <l>Full ſoon would fetch him hence.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>I that is true the Young-man ſaid,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>I that is true, ſaid he,</l>
                  <l>Or if they were neer to this place,</l>
                  <l>They ſoon would ſet him free.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But fare thou well thou good old man,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                     </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Farewel, and thanks to thee:</l>
                  <l>If <hi>Stutly</hi> hanged be this day,</l>
                  <l>Reveng'd his death will be.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>He was no ſooner from the Palmer gone,
<pb facs="tcp:35608:17"/>
                     <hi>derry derry down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>But the Gates was opened wide,</l>
                  <l>And out of the Caſtle <hi>Will Stutly</hi> came,</l>
                  <l>Guarded on every ſide.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>When he was forth of the Caſtle come,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And ſaw no help was nigh,</l>
                  <l>Thus he did ſay unto the Sheriff,</l>
                  <l>Thus he ſaid gallantly.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Now ſeeing that I needs muſt dye,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Grant me one boon, ſays he,</l>
                  <l>For my noble Maſter ne'r had Man</l>
                  <l>That yet was hang'd on the tree.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Give me a Sword all in my hand,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And let me be unbound:</l>
                  <l>And with thee and thy men i'le fight,</l>
                  <l>Vntil I lye dead on the ground.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But his deſire he would not grant,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>His wiſhes were in vain,</l>
                  <l>For the Sheriff had ſworn he hang'd ſhould be</l>
                  <l>And not by the Sword be ſlain.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:18"/>
                  <l>Do but unbind my hands he ſays,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>I will no weapons crave,</l>
                  <l>And if I hanged be this day,</l>
                  <l>Damnation let me have.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>O no, O no, the Sheriff he ſaid,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Thou ſhalt on the Gallows dye:</l>
                  <l>I, and ſo ſhall thy Maſter too,</l>
                  <l>If ever in me it lye.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>O daſtard Coward <hi>Stutly</hi> cries,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Thou faint-hearted Peaſant ſlave,</l>
                  <l>If ever my Maſter do thee meet,</l>
                  <l>Thou ſhalt thy payment have.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>My noble Maſter thee doth ſcorn,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And all thy <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>owardly crew,</l>
                  <l>Such ſilly imps unable are,</l>
                  <l>Bold <hi>Robin</hi> to ſubdue.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But when he was to the Gallows come,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And ready to bid adieu:</l>
                  <l>Out of a Buſh leaps Little <hi>John,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And ſteps <hi>Will Stutly</hi> too.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:18"/>
                  <l>I pray thee <hi>Will</hi> before thou dye,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Of thy dear friends take leave,</l>
                  <l>I needs muſt borrow him a while,</l>
                  <l>How ſay you Maſter Sheriff?</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Now as I live the Sheriff he ſaid,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>That Varlet well I know,</l>
                  <l>Some ſturdy Rebel is that ſame,</l>
                  <l>Therefore let him not go.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>With that Little <hi>John</hi> ſo haſtily,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Away cut <hi>Stutly's</hi> bands,</l>
                  <l>And from one of the Sheriff his men,</l>
                  <l>A ſword twitcht from his hands.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Here <hi>Will,</hi> here take thou this ſame,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Thou canſt it better ſway,</l>
                  <l>And here defend thy ſelf a while,</l>
                  <l>For aid will come ſtraight-way.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>And there they turn'd them back to back,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>In the middle of them that day,</l>
                  <l>Till <hi>Robin hood</hi> approached near,</l>
                  <l>With many an Archer gay.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:19"/>
                  <l>With that an Arrow by them flew,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>I wiſt from <hi>Robin hood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Make haſt, make haſt, the Sheriff he ſaid,</l>
                  <l>Make haſt, for it is good.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The Sheriff is gone, his doubtleſs men,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry, derry, down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Thought it no boot to ſtay:</l>
                  <l>But as their Maſter had them taught,</l>
                  <l>They ran full faſt away.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>O ſtay, O ſtay, <hi>Will Stutly</hi> ſaid,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry, derry, down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Take leave e're you depart,</l>
                  <l>You ne'r will catch hold <hi>Robin Hood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Vnleſs you dare him ſtart.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>O ill betide you, quoth <hi>Robin Hood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry, derry, down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>That you ſo ſoon are gone,</l>
                  <l>My Sword may in the Scabbard reſt,</l>
                  <l>For here our work is done.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>I little thought when I came here,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry, derry, down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>When I came here to this place,</l>
                  <l>For to have met with Little <hi>John,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Or ſeen my Maſters face.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:19"/>
                  <l>Thus <hi>Stutly</hi> was at liberty ſet,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry, derry, down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And ſafe brought from his foe,</l>
                  <l>O thanks, O thanks to my Maſter,</l>
                  <l>Since here it was not ſo.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>And once again my fellows all,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry, derry, down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>We ſhall in the green Woods meet:</l>
                  <l>Where we will make our bow-ſtrings twang</l>
                  <l>Muſick for us moſt ſweet,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>hey down, derry derry down.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>Robin Hood <hi>and the Begger. Shewing how</hi> Robin Hood <hi>and the Begger fought: and how he changed cloaths with the Begger; and how he went a begging to</hi> Nottingham: <hi>and how he ſaved three bre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thren from hanging for ſtealing of Deer.</hi>
               </head>
               <opener>
                  <hi>To the T<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ne of, Robin Hood and the ſtranger.</hi>
               </opener>
               <lg>
                  <l>COme light and liſten you Gentlemen all,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>hey down down and a down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>That mirth do love for to hear,</l>
                  <l>and a ſtory true, i'le tell unto you,</l>
                  <l>If that you will draw near.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>In elder times when merriment was,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:20"/>
                  <l>And Archery was holden good,</l>
                  <l>there was an Out-law, as many did know,</l>
                  <l>Which men called <hi>Robin Hood.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Vpon a time it chanced ſo,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Bold <hi>Robin</hi> was merry diſpos'd:</l>
                  <l>his time to ſpend, he did intend,</l>
                  <l>Either with friends or foes.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then he got up on a gallant brave Steed,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>The which was worth Angels ten,</l>
                  <l>with a mantle of green, moſt brave to be ſeen</l>
                  <l>He left all his merry men.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ndriding towards fair <hi>Nottingham,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Some paſtime for to ſpy,</l>
                  <l>There was he aware of a jolly Begger,</l>
                  <l>As e're he beheld with his eye.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>An old patcht Coat the Begger had on,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Which he daily did uſe for to wear,</l>
                  <l>and many a bag about him did wag,</l>
                  <l>Which made <hi>Robin Hood</hi> to him repair.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>God-ſpeed, God-ſpeed, ſaid <hi>Robin hood</hi> then,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:20"/>
                  <l>What Countrey-man, tell unto me,</l>
                  <l>I am <hi>Yorkſhire</hi> Sir, but e're you go far,</l>
                  <l>Some charity give unto me.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Why what wouldſt thou have, ſaid <hi>Rob. hood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>I pray tell unto me,</l>
                  <l>no lands nor living, the begger he ſaid,</l>
                  <l>But a penny for charity.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>I have no money, ſaid <hi>Robin hood</hi> then,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>But a Ranger within the wood,</l>
                  <l>I am an Out-law, as many do know,</l>
                  <l>My Name it is <hi>Robin hood.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But yet I muſt tell thee bonny begger,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>That about with thee I muſt try,</l>
                  <l>thy coat of gray, lay down I ſay,</l>
                  <l>And my mantle of green ſhall lye by.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Content, content, the begger he cry'd,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Thy part it will be the worſe;</l>
                  <l>for I hope this bout to give thee the rout,</l>
                  <l>And then have at thy Purſe.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The begger he had a mickle long ſtaff,
<pb facs="tcp:35608:21"/>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>And <hi>Robin</hi> had a nut-brown ſword,</l>
                  <l>ſo the begger drew nigh, &amp; at <hi>Robin</hi> let fly,</l>
                  <l>But gave him never a Word.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Fight on, fight on, ſaid <hi>Robin Hood</hi> then,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>This Game well pleaſeth me,</l>
                  <l>For every blow that <hi>Robin</hi> did give,</l>
                  <l>The Begger gave buffets three.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>And fighting there full hard and ſore,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Not far from <hi>Nottingham</hi> town,</l>
                  <l>they never fled, till from <hi>Robins</hi> head</l>
                  <l>The blood ran trickling down.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>O hold thy hand, ſaid <hi>Robin hood</hi> then,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>And thou and I will agree,</l>
                  <l>if that be true the begger he ſaid,</l>
                  <l>Thy Mantle come give unto me.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Now a change, a change, cry'd <hi>Robin hood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Thy bags and Coat give me,</l>
                  <l>&amp; this Mantle of mine, i'le to thee reſign,</l>
                  <l>My Horſe and my bravery.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:21"/>
                  <l>When <hi>Robin</hi> had got the beggers cloaths,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>He looked round about,</l>
                  <l>methinks ſaid he, I ſeem to be,</l>
                  <l>A begger brave and ſtout.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>For now I have a bag for my bread,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>So have I another for Corn,</l>
                  <l>I have one for Salt, and another for malt,</l>
                  <l>And one for my little Horn.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>And now I will a begging go,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Some charity for to find,</l>
                  <l>and if any more of <hi>Robin</hi> you'l know,</l>
                  <l>In this ſecond part it's behind.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Now <hi>Robin</hi> he is to <hi>Nottingham</hi> bound,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>With his bags hanging down to his knee,</l>
                  <l>his ſtuff and his coat, ſcarce worth a groat,</l>
                  <l>Yet merrily paſſed he.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>As <hi>Robin</hi> he paſſed the ſtreets along,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>He heard a pittiful cry,</l>
                  <l>three brethren dear, as he did hear,</l>
                  <l>Condemned were for to dye.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:22"/>
                  <l>Then <hi>Robin</hi> he hyed to the Sheriffs houſe,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Some relief for to ſeek,</l>
                  <l>he skipt and leapt, and capered full high,</l>
                  <l>As he went along the ſtreet.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But when to the Sheriffs houſe he came,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>There a Gentleman fine and brave,</l>
                  <l>thou begger ſaid he, come tell unto me,</l>
                  <l>What is it that thou wouldeſt have?</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>No meat nor drink, ſaid <hi>Robin hood</hi> then,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>That I come here to crave,</l>
                  <l>but to beg the lives of Yeomen three,</l>
                  <l>And that I fain would have.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>That cannot be thou bold begger,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Their fact it is ſo clear,</l>
                  <l>I tell to thee, they hanged muſt be,</l>
                  <l>For ſtealing of our Kings Deer.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But when to the Gallows they did come,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>There was many a weeping eye,</l>
                  <l>O hold your peace, ſaid <hi>Robin</hi> then,</l>
                  <l>For certainly they ſhall not dye.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:22"/>
                  <l>Then <hi>Robin</hi> he ſet his Horn to his mouth,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And blew but blaſts three,</l>
                  <l>till a hundred bold Archers brave</l>
                  <l>Came kneeling down to his knee.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>What is your will Maſter? they ſaid,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>We are here at your command,</l>
                  <l>ſhoot Eaſt, ſhoot Weſt, ſaid <hi>Robin</hi> then,</l>
                  <l>And look that you ſpare no man.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then they ſhot, Eaſt, and thy ſhot Weſt,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Their Arrows were ſo keen,</l>
                  <l>the Sheriff he, and his company,</l>
                  <l>No longer could be ſeen.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then he ſtept to theſe brethren three,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>And away he them had tane,</l>
                  <l>the Sheriff was croſt, and many a man loſt</l>
                  <l>That dead lay on the plain.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>And away they went into the merry green<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wood,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>And ſung with a merry glee,</l>
                  <l>And <hi>Robin</hi> took theſe brethren good</l>
                  <l>To be of his Yeomandree.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <pb facs="tcp:35608:23"/>
               <head>
                  <hi>Renowned</hi> Robin Hood: <hi>Or, His Famous Archery truly related, with the Worthy Exploits he acted before Queen</hi> Katherine, <hi>he being an Out-law-Man, and how ſhe for the ſame obtained of the King his own, and his fellows pardon.</hi>
               </head>
               <opener>To a new Tune.</opener>
               <lg>
                  <l>GOld tane from the Kings Harbengers,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a down a down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>As ſeldom hath been ſeen,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a down a down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And carried by bold <hi>Robin Hood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>for a preſent to the Queen;</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a down a down.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>If that I live one year to an end,</l>
                  <l>thus gan Queen <hi>Katherine</hi> ſay,</l>
                  <l>Bold <hi>Robin Hood</hi> I will be thy friend,</l>
                  <l>and all thy Yeomen gay.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The Queen is to her Chamber gone,</l>
                  <l>as faſt as ſhe can wen,</l>
                  <l>She calls unto her lovely Page,</l>
                  <l>his name was <hi>Richard Patrington.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Come hither to me thou lovely Page,</l>
                  <l>come thou hither to me:</l>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:23"/>
                  <l>For thou muſt Poſt to <hi>Nottingham,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l> as faſt as thou canſt dree.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>And as thou goeſt to <hi>Nottingham,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l> ſearch all thoſe Engliſh Woods,</l>
                  <l>Enquire of one good Yeoman or another,</l>
                  <l>that can tell thee of <hi>Robin hood.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Sometimes he went, ſometimes he ran,</l>
                  <l>as faſt as he could wen:</l>
                  <l>And when he came to <hi>Nottingham,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l> there he took up his Inn.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>And when he came to <hi>Nottingham,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l> and had took up his Inn,</l>
                  <l>He calls for a pottle of Rheniſh Wine,</l>
                  <l>and drinks a health to his Queen.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>There ſat a Yeoman by his ſide,</l>
                  <l>tell me ſweet Page, ſaid he,</l>
                  <l>What is thy buſineſs, or thy cauſe,</l>
                  <l>ſo far in the North Country.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>This is my buſineſs,</l>
                  <l>and my cauſe,</l>
                  <l>Sir, i'le tell it you for good,</l>
                  <l>To enquire of one good Yeoman, or another,</l>
                  <l>to tell me of <hi>Robin Hood.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>I'le get my horſe betimes in the morn,
<pb facs="tcp:35608:24"/>
by it be break of day,</l>
                  <l>And I will ſhew thee bold <hi>Robin hood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l> and all his Yeomen gay.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>When that he came at <hi>Robin Hoods</hi> place,</l>
                  <l>he fell down on his knee;</l>
                  <l>Queen <hi>Katherine</hi> ſhe doth greet you well,</l>
                  <l>ſhe greets you well<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> by me.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>She bids you poſt to fair <hi>London</hi> Court,</l>
                  <l>not fearing any thing,</l>
                  <l>For there ſhall be a little ſport,</l>
                  <l>and ſhe hath ſent you her Ring.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Robin</hi> took his Mantle from his back,</l>
                  <l>it was of the <hi>Lincoln</hi> green,</l>
                  <l>And ſent it by this lovely Page,</l>
                  <l>for a preſent to the Queen.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>In Summer time when leaves grow green,</l>
                  <l>it is a ſeemly ſight to ſee,</l>
                  <l>How <hi>Robin hood</hi> himſelf had dreſt,</l>
                  <l>and all his Yeomandree.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>He cloathed his men in <hi>Lincoln</hi> green,</l>
                  <l>and himſelf in Scarlet red,</l>
                  <l>Black hats, white feathers all alike,</l>
                  <l>now bold <hi>Robin hood</hi> is rid.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:24"/>
                  <l>And when he came at <hi>Londons</hi> Court,</l>
                  <l>he fell down on his knee,</l>
                  <l>Thou art welcome <hi>Lockſly,</hi> ſaid the Queen,</l>
                  <l>and all thy Yeomandree.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The King's gone into <hi>Finsbury</hi> field,</l>
                  <l>marching in battle ray;</l>
                  <l>And after follows bold <hi>Robin hood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l> and all his Yeomen gay:</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Come hither <hi>Tepus,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l> ſaid the King,</l>
                  <l>Bow-bearer after me,</l>
                  <l>Come meaſure me out with this Line,</l>
                  <l>how long our mark ſhall be.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>What is the Wager, ſaid the Queen,</l>
                  <l>that muſt I now know here,</l>
                  <l>Three hundred Tun of Rheniſh Wine,</l>
                  <l>three hundred Tun of Beer.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Three hundred of the fatteſt Harts</l>
                  <l>that run on <hi>Dallom</hi> Lee:</l>
                  <l>That's a Princely wager, ſaid the King,</l>
                  <l>that needs muſt I tell thee.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>With that beſpake one <hi>Clifton</hi> then,</l>
                  <l>full quickly and full ſoon;</l>
                  <l>Meaſure no mark for us moſt Soveraign Liege,</l>
                  <l>we'l ſhoot at Sun and Moon.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:25"/>
                  <l>Full fifteen ſcore your mark ſhall be,</l>
                  <l>full fifteen ſcore ſhall ſtand:</l>
                  <l>I'le lay my Bow, ſaid <hi>Clifton</hi> then,</l>
                  <l>i'le cleave the Willow Wand.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>With that the Kings Archers led about,</l>
                  <l>while it was three and none,</l>
                  <l>With that the Ladies began to ſhout,</l>
                  <l>Madam, your Game is gone.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>A boon, a boon, Queen <hi>Katherine</hi> cries,</l>
                  <l>I crave on my bare knee:</l>
                  <l>Is there ever a <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>t. of your Privy-Counſel,</l>
                  <l>on Queen <hi>Katherines</hi> part will be?</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Come hither to me Sir <hi>Richard Lee,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l> thou art a Knight full good:</l>
                  <l>For I do know by thy Pedigree,</l>
                  <l>thou ſprang'ſt from <hi>Gowers</hi> blood.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Come hither to me thou Biſhop of <hi>Hereford<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhire,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l> for a Noble Prieſt was he,</l>
                  <l>By my Silver Miter, ſaid the Biſhop then,</l>
                  <l>I'le not bet one penny.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The King hath Archers of his own,</l>
                  <l>full ready and full light,</l>
                  <l>And theſe be ſtrangers every one,</l>
                  <l>no man knows what they height.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:25"/>
                  <l>What wilt thou bet? ſaid <hi>Robin hood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l> thou ſeeſt our Games the worſe:</l>
                  <l>By my ſilver Miter, ſaid the Biſhop then,</l>
                  <l>all the money within my purſe.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>What is in thy purſe, ſaid <hi>Robin hood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l> throw it <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>own on the ground:</l>
                  <l>Fifteenſcore Nobles, ſaid the Biſhop then,</l>
                  <l>it's neer an hundred pound.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Robin hood</hi> took his bag from his ſide,</l>
                  <l>and threw it down on the Green:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Will Scadlock</hi> went ſmiling away,</l>
                  <l>I know who this money muſt win.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>With that the Kings Archers led about,</l>
                  <l>while it was three and three,</l>
                  <l>With that the Ladies gave a ſhout,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Woodcock</hi> beware thy knee.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>It is three, and three, now ſaid the King,</l>
                  <l>the next three pays for all:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Robin hood</hi> went &amp; whiſpered to the Queen,</l>
                  <l>the Kings part ſhall be but ſmall.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Robin hood</hi> he led about,</l>
                  <l>he ſhot it under-hand,</l>
                  <l>And <hi>Clifton</hi> with a bearing-Arrow,</l>
                  <l>he clave the Willow-wand.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:26"/>
                  <l>And little <hi>Midge</hi> the Millers Son,</l>
                  <l>he ſhot not much the worſe,</l>
                  <l>He ſhot within a finger of the Prick,</l>
                  <l>now Biſhop beware thy Purſe.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>A boon, a boon, Queen <hi>Katherine</hi> tries,</l>
                  <l>I crave that on my bare knee,</l>
                  <l>That you will angry he with none,</l>
                  <l>that is of my party.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>They ſhall have forty days to come,</l>
                  <l>and forty days to go,</l>
                  <l>And three times forty to ſport and play,</l>
                  <l>then welcome every one.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then thou art welcome <hi>Robin Hood</hi> ſaid the Queen,</l>
                  <l>and ſo is little <hi>Iohn,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>So is <hi>Midge</hi> the Millers Son,</l>
                  <l>thrice welcome every one.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Is this <hi>Robin hood</hi> the King now ſaid?</l>
                  <l>for it was told to me,</l>
                  <l>That he was ſlain in the Pallace gate,</l>
                  <l>ſo far in the North Country.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Is this <hi>Robin hood?</hi> quoth the Biſhop then,</l>
                  <l>as it ſeems well to be,</l>
                  <l>Had I known he had been that bold Out-law</l>
                  <l>I would not a bet one penny.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:26"/>
                  <l>He took me late one Saturday-night,</l>
                  <l>and bound me faſt to a tree;</l>
                  <l>And made me ſing a Maſs, God wot,</l>
                  <l>to him and his Yeomen three.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>What and if I did, ſays <hi>Robin hood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l> of that Maſs I was full fain:</l>
                  <l>For recompence to thee, he ſays,</l>
                  <l>here's half thy Gold again.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Now nay, now nay, ſays little <hi>John,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down, a down, a down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Maſter that may not be,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down, a down, a down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>We muſt give gifts to the Kings Officers,</l>
                  <l>that Gold will ſerve thee and me:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down, a down, a down.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>Robin Hood <hi>and the Tanner: Or, </hi> Robin Hood <hi>met with his match. A merry and pleaſant Song, relating the gal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lant and fierce Combate fought between</hi> Arthur Bland <hi>a Tanner of</hi> Nottingham, <hi>and</hi> Robin Hood <hi>the greateſt and moſt no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bleſt Archer of</hi> England.</head>
               <opener>
                  <hi>The Tune is, </hi> Robin Hood <hi>and the Stranger.</hi>
               </opener>
               <lg>
                  <l>IN <hi>Nottingham</hi> there lives a jolly Tinker,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey down, down a down down, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:27"/>
                  <l>His name is <hi>Ar<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>hur a Bland, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>There is never a Squire in <hi>Nottinghamſhire,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l> dare bid bold <hi>Arthur</hi> ſtand.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>With a long Pike-ſtaff upon his ſhoulder,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>So well he can clear his way:</l>
                  <l>By two and by three, he makes them to <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>lee,</l>
                  <l>for he hath no liſt to ſtay.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>And as he went forth in a ſummers morning <hi>with a hey,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Into the Forreſt of merry <hi>Sherwood, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>To view the red Deer, that range here &amp; there,</l>
                  <l>there met he with bold <hi>Robin hood.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>As ſoon as hold <hi>Robin hood</hi> did him eſpy,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>He thought ſome ſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ort he would make:</l>
                  <l>Therefore out of hand he did him to ſtand,</l>
                  <l>and thus unto him he ſpake.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Why, what art thou, thou bold fellow,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>That ranges ſo boldly here, </l>
                  <l>In ſooth to be brief, thou look'ſt like a thief,</l>
                  <l>that comes to ſteal our Kings Deer.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>For I am a Keeper in this Forreſt,
<pb facs="tcp:35608:27"/>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>The King puts me in truſt, </l>
                  <l>To look to his Deer, that range here and ther<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>therefore ſtay thee I muſt.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>If thou beeſt a Keeper in this Forreſt,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>And hath ſuch a great command, </l>
                  <l>Yet thou muſt have more partakers in ſtore,</l>
                  <l>before that you make me ſtand.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>No, I have no more partakers in ſtore,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Or any that I do need;</l>
                  <l>But I have a ſtaff of another Oak graft,</l>
                  <l>I know it will do the deed.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>For thy ſword and thy bow, I care not a ſtraw</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Nor all thine Arrows to boot, </l>
                  <l>If thou get'ſt a knock, upon thy bare ſcop,</l>
                  <l>you canſt as well ſhite as ſhoot.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Speak cleanly, good fellow, ſaid jolly <hi>Robin,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>And give better terms to me:</l>
                  <l>Elſe i'le thee correct for thy neglect,</l>
                  <l>and make thee more mannerly.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:28"/>
                  <l>Marry gap with a wenion, qd. <hi>Arthur Bland,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Art thou ſuch a goodly man?</l>
                  <l>I care not a fig for thy looking ſo big,</l>
                  <l>mend thou thy ſelf how thou can.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then <hi>Robin hood</hi> he unbuckled his belt,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>And laid down his bow ſo long, </l>
                  <l>He took up a Staff of another Oak-graft,</l>
                  <l>that was both ſtiff and ſtrong.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>I yield to thy weapon, ſaid jolly <hi>Robin,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Since thou wilt not yield to mine, </l>
                  <l>For I have a Staff of another Oak-graft,</l>
                  <l>not half a foot longer then thine.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But let me meaſure, ſaid jolly <hi>Robin,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Before we begin our fray, </l>
                  <l>For i'le not have mine to be longer then thine,</l>
                  <l>for that will be counted foul play.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>I paſs not for length, bold <hi>Arthur</hi> replyed,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>My Staff is of Oak ſo free, </l>
                  <l>Eight foot &amp; a half, it will knock down a Calf,</l>
                  <l>and I hope it will knock down thee.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:28"/>
                  <l>Then <hi>Robin</hi> he could no longer forbear,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>He gave him ſuch a knock, </l>
                  <l>Quickly and ſoon the blood ran down,</l>
                  <l>before it was ten a clock.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then <hi>Arthur</hi> he ſoon recovered himſelf,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>And gave him ſuch a knock on the crown, </l>
                  <l>That from every hair on <hi>Robins</hi> head,</l>
                  <l>the blood it ran trickling down.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then <hi>Robin hood</hi> raged like a wild Boar,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>As ſoon as he ſaw his own blood, </l>
                  <l>Then <hi>Bland</hi> was in haſt he laid on ſo faſt,</l>
                  <l>as though he had been cleaving of wood.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>And about, and about, and about they went,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Like two wild Boars in a chaſe, </l>
                  <l>Striving to aim, each other to maim,</l>
                  <l>leg, arm, or any other place.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>And knock for knock they luſtily dealt,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Which held for two hours and more, </l>
                  <l>That all the wood rang at every bang,</l>
                  <l>they ply'd their work ſo ſore.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:29"/>
                  <l>But if thou wilt forſake thy Tanners trade,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>And live in green Wood with me, </l>
                  <l>My Name's <hi>Robin hood, </hi> I ſwear by the wood</l>
                  <l>I will give thee both gold and fee.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>If thou be <hi>Robin hood, </hi> bold <hi>Arthur</hi> reply'd,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>As I think well thou art, </l>
                  <l>then here's my hand, my names <hi>Arthur Bland</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>we two will never depart.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But tell me, O tell me, where is little <hi>Iohn,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Of him fain would I hear, </l>
                  <l>For we are ally'd by the Mothers ſide,</l>
                  <l>and he is my Rinſman neer.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then <hi>Robin hood</hi> he blew on the beagle horn</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>He blew both loud and ſhrill, </l>
                  <l>But quickly anon, appear'd little <hi>Iohn,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l> come tripping down a green hill.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>O what is the matter, then ſaid little <hi>Iohn,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Maſter I pray you tell, </l>
                  <l>Why do you ſtand with your ſtaff in hand,</l>
                  <l>I fear all is not well.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:29"/>
                  <l>Hold thy hand, hold thy hand, ſaid <hi>Robin hood</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>And let our quarrel fall, </l>
                  <l>For here we may threſh our bones to maſh,</l>
                  <l>and get no coyn at all.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>And in the Forreſt of merry <hi>Sherwood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Hereafter thou ſhalt be free, </l>
                  <l>Godamercy for nought, my freedom I bought</l>
                  <l>I may thank my good ſtaff, and not thee.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>What tradeſ-man art thou, ſaid jolly <hi>Robin,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Good fellow I prithee me ſhow, </l>
                  <l>And alſo me tell, in what place you do dwell,</l>
                  <l>for both theſe fain would I know.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>I am a Tanner bold <hi>Arthur</hi> reply'd,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>In <hi>Nottingham</hi> long have I wrought, </l>
                  <l>And if thou come there, I vow and do ſwear,</l>
                  <l>I will tan thy hide for naught.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Godamercy good-Fellow, ſaid jolly <hi>Robin,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Since thou art ſo kind and free, </l>
                  <l>And if thou wilt tan my hide for naught,</l>
                  <l>I will do as much for thee.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:30"/>
                  <l>O man I do ſtand, and he makes me to ſtand,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>The Tanner that ſtands me beſide, </l>
                  <l>He is a bonny blade, and Maſter of his trade,</l>
                  <l>for ſoundly he hath tan'd my hide.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>He is to be commended, then ſaid little <hi>John,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>If ſuch a feat he can do:</l>
                  <l>If he be ſo ſtout, we will have a bout,</l>
                  <l>and he ſhall tan my hide too.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Hold thy hand, hold thy hand, ſaid <hi>Robin hood</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>For as I do underſtand, </l>
                  <l>He's a Yeoman good, and of thine own blood for his name is</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Arthur a Bland.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then little <hi>Iohn</hi> threw his ſtaff away,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>As far as he could it fling:</l>
                  <l>And ran out of hand to <hi>Arthur a Bland,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l> and about his neck did cling.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>With loving reſpect, there was no neglect,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>They were neither nice nor coy, </l>
                  <l>Each other did face with a lovely grace,</l>
                  <l>they both did weep for joy.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:30"/>
                  <l>Then <hi>Robin hood</hi> took him by the hand,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>And danced about the Oak-tree:</l>
                  <l>For three merry men, and three merry men,</l>
                  <l>and three merry men we be.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>And ever hereafter ſo long as we live,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>We three will be all one:</l>
                  <l>The wood it ſhall ring, and the old wife ſing,</l>
                  <l>of <hi>Robin hood, Arthur, </hi> and <hi>Iohn.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>
                  <hi>The famous Battel between</hi> Robin Hood <hi>and the Curtal Fryer, neer Fountain Dale.</hi>
               </head>
               <opener>To a new Northern Tune.</opener>
               <lg>
                  <l>IN Summer time when leaves grow green,</l>
                  <l>and flowers are freſh and gay, </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Robin hood</hi> and his merry men,</l>
                  <l>were diſpoſed to play.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then ſome would leap, and ſome would run,</l>
                  <l>and ſome would uſe Artiſſery:</l>
                  <l>Which of you can a good Bow draw,</l>
                  <l>a good Archer to be?</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Which of you can kill a Buck,</l>
                  <l>or who can kill a Doe?</l>
                  <l>Or who can kill a Hart of <hi>Greece, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:31"/>
                  <l>five hundred foot him fro.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Will Scadlock</hi> he kill'd a Buck,</l>
                  <l>and <hi>Midge</hi> he kill'd a Doe, </l>
                  <l>And little <hi>John</hi> kill'd a Hart of <hi>Greece,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l> five hundred foot him fro.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Gods bleſſing on thy heart, ſaid <hi>Robin Hood</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>that ſhot ſuch a ſhot for me, </l>
                  <l>I would ride my horſe an hundred miles,</l>
                  <l>to find one could match thee.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>That cauſed <hi>Will Scadlock</hi> to laugh,</l>
                  <l>he laughed full heartily;</l>
                  <l>There lives a Fryer in Fountain-Abby,</l>
                  <l>will beat both him and thee.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>That Curtal Fryer in Fountain-Abby,</l>
                  <l>well can a ſtrong Bow draw, </l>
                  <l>He will beat you and your Yeomen,</l>
                  <l>ſet them all on a row.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Robin Hood</hi> took a ſolemn Oath,</l>
                  <l>it was by <hi>Mary</hi> free, </l>
                  <l>That he would neither eat nor drink,</l>
                  <l>till the Fryer he did ſee.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Robin Hood</hi> put on his Harneſs good,</l>
                  <l>and on his head a Cap of Steel, </l>
                  <l>Then
<pb facs="tcp:35608:31"/>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>oad Sword and Buckler by his ſide,</l>
                  <l>and they became him weel.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> took his Bow into his hand,</l>
                  <l>it was made of a truſty Tree, </l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ith a ſheaf of Arrows at his Belt,</l>
                  <l>to the Fountains-Dale went he.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>nd coming to the Fountain-Dale,</l>
                  <l>no further would he ride, </l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>here was he ware of a Curtal Fry<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>r,</l>
                  <l>walking by the water ſide.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>he Fryer had on a harneſs good,</l>
                  <l>and on his head a Cap of Steel, </l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>road Sword and Buckler by his ſide,</l>
                  <l>and they became him weel.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>obin Hood</hi> lighted off from his horſe,</l>
                  <l>and tyed him to a Thorn, </l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>arry me over the water, thou Curtal Fryer,</l>
                  <l>or elſe thy life's forlorn.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>he Fryer took <hi>Robin Hood</hi> on his back,</l>
                  <l>deep water he did beſtride, </l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>nd ſpake neither good word nor bad,</l>
                  <l>till he came at the other ſide.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ightly ſtept <hi>Robin</hi> off the Fryers back,
<pb facs="tcp:35608:32"/>
the Fryer ſaid to him again:</l>
                  <l>Carry me over this water, fine fellow,</l>
                  <l>or it ſhall breed thy pain.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Robin hood</hi> took the Fryer on's back,</l>
                  <l>deep water he did beſtride, </l>
                  <l>And ſpake neither good word nor bad,</l>
                  <l>till he came at the other ſide.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Lightly leapt the Fryer off <hi>Robin hoods</hi> ba<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Robin hood</hi> ſaid to him again:</l>
                  <l>Carry me over this water thou curtal Frye<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>or it ſhall breed thy pain.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The Fryer took <hi>Robin hood</hi> on's back aga<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>and ſtept up to the knee,</l>
                  <l>Till he came to the middle ſtream,</l>
                  <l>neither good nor bad ſpake he.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>And coming to the middle ſtream,</l>
                  <l>there he threw <hi>Robin</hi> in:</l>
                  <l>And chuſe thee, chuſe thee fine fellow,</l>
                  <l>whether thou wilt ſink or ſwim.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Robin hood</hi> ſwam to a buſh of Broom,</l>
                  <l>the Fryer to a wigger-wand:</l>
                  <l>Bold <hi>Robin hood</hi> is gone to ſhore,</l>
                  <l>and took his Low in hand.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:32"/>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap>e of the beſt Arrows under his Belt,</l>
                  <l>to the Fryer he let flye:</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap>e Curtal Fryer with his ſteel buckler</l>
                  <l>he put that Arrow by.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>oot on, ſhoot on, thou fine fellow,</l>
                  <l>ſhoot as thou haſt begun;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> thou ſhoot here a Summers day,</l>
                  <l>thy mark I will not ſhun.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>obin hood</hi> ſhot ſo paſſing well,</l>
                  <l>till his Arrows all were gone:</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>hey took their Swords and Steel bucklers,</l>
                  <l>and fought with might and main.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap>om ten o'th clock that day,</l>
                  <l>till four i'th afternoon:</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap>en <hi>Robin hood</hi> came to knees</l>
                  <l>of Fryer to beg a boon.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> boon, a boon, thou Curtal Fryer,</l>
                  <l>I beg it on my knee, </l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ive me leave to ſet my Horn to my mouth,</l>
                  <l>and to blow blaſts three.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>hat will I do, ſaid the Curtal Fryer,</l>
                  <l>of thy blaſts I have no doubt, </l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> hope thou'lt blow ſo paſſing well,</l>
                  <l>till both thy eyes fall out.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:33"/>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Robin Hood</hi> ſet his Hom to his mouth,</l>
                  <l>he blew but blaſts three;</l>
                  <l>Half a hundred Yeomen with Bows bent,</l>
                  <l>came ranging over the Lee.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Whoſe men are theſe, ſaid the Fryer,</l>
                  <l>that come ſo haſtily?</l>
                  <l>Theſe are mine, ſaid <hi>Robin Hood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l> Fryer what's that to thee?</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>A boon, a boon, ſaid the Curtal Fryer,</l>
                  <l>the like I gave to thee, </l>
                  <l>Give me leave to ſet my Fiſt to my mouth,</l>
                  <l>and to whute whutes three.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>That will I do, ſaid <hi>Robin Hood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l> or elſe I were to blame, </l>
                  <l>Three whutes in a Fryers Fiſt,</l>
                  <l>would make glad and fain.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The Fryer he ſet his Fiſt to his mouth,</l>
                  <l>and whuted whutes three, </l>
                  <l>Half a hundred good Bay Dogs,</l>
                  <l>came running the Fryer unto.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Here's for every man a Dog,</l>
                  <l>and I my ſelf for thee, </l>
                  <l>Nay, by my faith, quoth <hi>Robin Hood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l> Fryer that may not be.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:33"/>
                  <l>Two Dogs at on<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>e <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>o <hi>Robin Hood</hi> did go,</l>
                  <l>the one behind the other b<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="3 letters">
                        <desc>•••</desc>
                     </gap>e;</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Robin Hoods</hi> Mantle of <hi>Lincoln</hi> green,</l>
                  <l>off from his back they <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ore.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>And whether his men ſhot Eaſt or Weſt,</l>
                  <l>or they ſhot North or South;</l>
                  <l>The Curtal Dogs ſo taught they were,</l>
                  <l>they caught the Arrows in their mouth.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Take up thy Dogs ſaid Little <hi>John,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l> Fryer at my bidding be;</l>
                  <l>Whoſe man art thou, ſaid the Curtal Fryer,</l>
                  <l>comes here to prate to me?</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>I am little <hi>John, Robin Hoods</hi> man,</l>
                  <l>Fryer I will not lye, </l>
                  <l>If thou take not up thy Dogs ſoon,</l>
                  <l>i'le take up them and thee.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Little <hi>John</hi> had a Bow in his hand,</l>
                  <l>he ſhot with might and main, </l>
                  <l>Soon half a ſcore of the Fryers Dogs,</l>
                  <l>lay dead upon the plain.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Hold thy hand, good fellow, ſaid the Curtal Fryer,</l>
                  <l>thy Maſter and I will agree, </l>
                  <l>And we will have new orders taken,</l>
                  <l>with all the haſt that may be.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:34"/>
                  <l>If thou wilt forſake fair fountains-Dale,</l>
                  <l>and fountains-Abby free:</l>
                  <l>Every Sunday throughout the year,</l>
                  <l>a Noble ſhall be thy fee.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>And every holy-day throughout the Year,</l>
                  <l>changed ſhall thy garments be, </l>
                  <l>If thou wilt go to fair <hi>Nottingham,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l> and there remain with me.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>This curtal Fryer had kept Fountains-dale,</l>
                  <l>ſeven long years and more:</l>
                  <l>There was neither Knight, Lord, nor Earl,</l>
                  <l>could make him yield before.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>
                  <hi>The Noble Fiſherman: Or;</hi> Robin Hood's <hi>Preferment: Shewing how he won a prize on the Sea, and how he gave one half to his Dame, and the other to the building of Alms-houſes.</hi>
               </head>
               <opener>
                  <hi>The Tune is, </hi> In Summer time.</opener>
               <lg>
                  <l>IN Summer time when leaves grow green,</l>
                  <l>when they do grow both green and long, </l>
                  <l>Of a bold Out-law call'd <hi>Robin hood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l> it is of him I ſing this ſong.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>When the Lilly-leaf and the Cowſlip ſweet</l>
                  <l>doth bud and ſpring with a merry chear, </l>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:34"/>
                  <l>This Out-law was weary of the wood-ſide,</l>
                  <l>and chaſing of the Fallow Deer.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The Fiſher-men brave more money have</l>
                  <l>then any Merchant two or three:</l>
                  <l>Therefore I will to <hi>Scarborough</hi> go,</l>
                  <l>that I a Fiſher-man brave may be.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>This Out-law call'd his merry men all,</l>
                  <l>as they ſat under the green-wood-tree, </l>
                  <l>If any of you have gold to ſpend,</l>
                  <l>I pray you heartily ſpend it with me.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Now, quoth <hi>Robin, </hi> i'le to <hi>Scarborough</hi> go,</l>
                  <l>it ſeems to be a very fair day, </l>
                  <l>Who took up his Inn at a Widdow-womans houſe,</l>
                  <l>hard by upon the waters gray.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Who asked of him where wert thou born,</l>
                  <l>or tell to me where doſt thou fare?</l>
                  <l>I am a poor Fiſher-man ſaid he then,</l>
                  <l>this day intrapped all in care.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>What is thy name thou fine fellow,</l>
                  <l>I pray thee heartily tell to me:</l>
                  <l>In mine own Country where I was born,</l>
                  <l>men call me <hi>Simon over the Lee.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Simon, Simon, </hi> ſaid the good wife,
<pb facs="tcp:35608:35"/>
I wiſh thou mayſt well brook thy name, </l>
                  <l>The Out-law was ware of her courteſie,</l>
                  <l>and rejoyced he had got ſuch a Dame.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Simon, </hi> wilt thou be my man?</l>
                  <l>and good round wages i'le give thee, </l>
                  <l>I have as good a Ship of mine own,</l>
                  <l>as any ſails upon the Sea.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Anchors and Planks thou ſhalt want none,</l>
                  <l>Maſts and Ropes that are ſo long, </l>
                  <l>And if that you thus furniſh me,</l>
                  <l>ſaid <hi>Simon, </hi> nothing ſhall go wrong.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>They pluckt up Anchor and away did ſail,</l>
                  <l>more of a day then two or three, </l>
                  <l>When others caſt in their baited hooks,</l>
                  <l>the bare lines into the Sea caſt he.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>It will be long, ſaid the Maſter then,</l>
                  <l>e're this great Lubber do thrive on the Sea, </l>
                  <l>He ſhall have no part of our Fiſh,</l>
                  <l>for in truth he is no part worthy.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>O woe is me, ſaid <hi>Simon</hi> then,</l>
                  <l>this day that ever I came here, </l>
                  <l>I wiſh I were in <hi>Plumpton</hi> Park,</l>
                  <l>in chaſing of the Fallow Deer.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:35"/>
                  <l>For every Clown laughs me to ſcorn,</l>
                  <l>and by me ſet noting at all, </l>
                  <l>If I had them in <hi>Plumpton</hi> Park,</l>
                  <l>I would ſet as little by them all.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>They pluckt up Anchor and away did ſail,</l>
                  <l>more of a day then two or three, </l>
                  <l>But <hi>Simon</hi> eſpyed a Shi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> of War,</l>
                  <l>that ſailed towards them valorouſly.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>O woe is me, ſaid the Maſter then,</l>
                  <l>this day that ever I was born, </l>
                  <l>For all the Fiſh that we have got,</l>
                  <l>is every bit loſt and forlorn.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>For you <hi>French</hi> Robber on the Sea,</l>
                  <l>they will not ſpare of us one man, </l>
                  <l>But carry us to the Coaſt of <hi>France,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l> and lay us in the Priſon ſtrong.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But <hi>Simon</hi> ſaid, do not fear them,</l>
                  <l>neither Maſter take you any care, </l>
                  <l>Give me my bent Bow in my hand,</l>
                  <l>and never a <hi>French-man</hi> will I ſpare.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Hold thy peace thou long Lubber,</l>
                  <l>for thou art naught but brags and boaſt, </l>
                  <l>If I ſhould caſt thee over-board,</l>
                  <l>there's but a ſimple Lubber loſt.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:36"/>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Simon</hi> grew angry at theſe words,</l>
                  <l>and ſo angry then was he, </l>
                  <l>That he took his bent bow in his hand,</l>
                  <l>and to the ſhip hatch go doth he.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Maſter tye me to the Maſt he ſaid,</l>
                  <l>that at my mark I may ſtand fair, </l>
                  <l>And give me my bent bow in my hand,</l>
                  <l>and never a <hi>French-man</hi> will I ſpare.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>He drew his Arrow to the very head,</l>
                  <l>and drew it with all might and main, </l>
                  <l>And ſtraightway in the twinkling of an eye,</l>
                  <l>doth the <hi>Frenchmans</hi> heart the arrow gain.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The <hi>Frenchman</hi> fell down on the ſhip-hatch,</l>
                  <l>and under the hatches down below, </l>
                  <l>Another <hi>Frenchman</hi> that him eſpyed,</l>
                  <l>the dead corps into the Sea doth throw.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>O Maſter looſe me from the Maſt he ſaid,</l>
                  <l>and for them all take you no care, </l>
                  <l>And give me my bent bow in my hand,</l>
                  <l>and never a <hi>Frenchman</hi> will I ſpare.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then ſtraight they boarded the <hi>French</hi> ſhip,</l>
                  <l>they lying all dead in their ſight, </l>
                  <l>They found within the Ship of War,</l>
                  <l>twelve thouſand pound in money bright.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:36"/>
                  <l>The one half of the Ship, ſaid <hi>Simon</hi> then,</l>
                  <l>i'le give to my Dame and children ſmall, </l>
                  <l>The other half of my Ship i'le give</l>
                  <l>to you that are my fellows all.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But now beſpake the Maſter then,</l>
                  <l>for ſo <hi>Simon</hi> it ſhall not be, </l>
                  <l>For you have won it with your own hands,</l>
                  <l>and the owner of it you muſt be.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>It ſhall be ſo as I have ſaid,</l>
                  <l>and with this gold for the oppreſt,</l>
                  <l>An habitation I will build,</l>
                  <l>where they ſhall live in peace and reſt.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>Robin Hood <hi>and the Shepheard. Shewing how</hi> Robin Hood, <hi>little</hi> Iohn, <hi>and the Shepherd, ſought a ſore Combat.</hi>
               </head>
               <opener>
                  <hi>Tune is, </hi> Robin Hood <hi>and Queen</hi> Ratherine.</opener>
               <lg>
                  <l>ALL Gentlemen and Yeomen good,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down, a down down, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>I wiſh you to draw near:</l>
                  <l>for a ſtory of gallant bold <hi>Robin hood, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Vnto you I will declare. <hi>down, a down down.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>As <hi>Robin hood</hi> walkt the Forreſt along,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down, a down down, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Some paſtime for to ſpy,</l>
                  <l>there was he ware of a jolly Shepherd, </l>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:37"/>
                  <l>That on the ground did lye, <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Ariſe, ariſe, ſaid joſly <hi>Robin,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>And now come let me ſee,</l>
                  <l>what is in thy bag and bottle I ſay, </l>
                  <l>Come tell it unto me:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>What's that to thee, thou proud fellow,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Tell me as I do ſtand,</l>
                  <l>what thou haſt to do with my bag &amp; bottle?</l>
                  <l>Let me ſee thy command:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>My Sword that hangeth by my ſide,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Is my command I know,</l>
                  <l>come and let me taſte of thy Bottle, </l>
                  <l>Or it may breed thée woe:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The Devil a drop thou proud fellow,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Of my bottle thou ſhalt ſee,</l>
                  <l>until thy valour here be try'd, </l>
                  <l>Whether thou wilt fight or flee:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:37"/>
                  <l>What ſhall we fight for, cries <hi>Robin Hood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Come tell it ſoon to me,</l>
                  <l>here's twenty pound in good red Gold, </l>
                  <l>Win it and take it thee:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The Shepherd ſtood all in a maze,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>And knew not what to ſay,</l>
                  <l>I have no money thou proud fellow, </l>
                  <l>But bag and bottle i'le lay:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>I am content thou Shepherd ſwain,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Fling them down on the ground,</l>
                  <l>but it will breed thee mickle pain, </l>
                  <l>To win my twenty pound:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Come draw thy Sword thou proud fellow,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Thou ſtandeſt too long to prate,</l>
                  <l>this Hook of mine ſhall let thee know, </l>
                  <l>A Coward I do hate:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>So they fell to it full hardy and ſore,
<pb facs="tcp:35608:38"/>
                     <hi>down a, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>It was on a Summers day,</l>
                  <l>from ten till four in the afternoon, </l>
                  <l>The Shepherd held him play,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Robin's</hi> Buckler proved his thiefeſt defence,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And ſaved him many a bang,</l>
                  <l>for every blow the Shepherd gave, </l>
                  <l>Made <hi>Robins</hi> ſword cry twang:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Many a ſturdy blow the Shepherd gave,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And that bold <hi>Robin</hi> found,</l>
                  <l>till the blood ran trickling from his head, </l>
                  <l>Then he fell to the ground:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Ariſe, ariſe, thou proud fellow,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And thou ſhalt have fair play,</l>
                  <l>if thou wilt yield before thou go, </l>
                  <l>That I have won the day:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>A boon, a boon, cryed bold <hi>Robin,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:38"/>
                  <l>If that a man thou be,</l>
                  <l>then let me take my beagle-horn, </l>
                  <l>And blow but blaſts three:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then ſaid the Shepherd to bold <hi>Robin,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>To that I will agree:</l>
                  <l>for if thou ſhouldſt blow till to morrow morn</l>
                  <l>I ſcorn one foot to flee:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then <hi>Robin</hi> he ſet his horn to his mouth,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>And he blew with might and main,</l>
                  <l>until he eſpyed little <hi>Iohn, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Come tripping over the Plain:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>O who is yonder thou proud fellow,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>That comes down yonder hill?</l>
                  <l>yonder is <hi>Iohn, </hi> bold <hi>Robin hoods</hi> man, </l>
                  <l>Shall fight with thee thy fill. <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>What is the matter, ſays little <hi>Iohn,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Maſter come tell to me:</l>
                  <l>my caſe is bad, crys <hi>Robin hood, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For the Shepherd hath conquered me:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:39"/>
                  <l>I am glad of that, cries little <hi>John,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Shepherd turn thou to me,</l>
                  <l>for about with thee I mean to have, </l>
                  <l>Either come fight or flee:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>With all my heart thou proud fellow,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>For it ſhall never be ſaid,</l>
                  <l>that a Shepherds hook, of thy ſturdy look, </l>
                  <l>Will one jot be diſmaid:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>So they fell to it full hardy and ſore,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Striving for victory;</l>
                  <l>I will know (ſays <hi>Iohn)</hi> e're we give o're, </l>
                  <l>Whether thou wilt fight or flee:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The Shepherd gave <hi>Iohn</hi> a ſturdy blow,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>With his hook under the Chin,</l>
                  <l>beſhrew thy heart, ſaid little <hi>Iohn, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Thou baſely doſt begin:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Nay, that is nothing, ſaid the Shepherd,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:39"/>
                  <l>Either yield to me the day, or I will bang thy back and ſides, </l>
                  <l>Before thou goeſt thy way:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>What doſt thou think thou proud fellow,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>That thou canſt conquer me,</l>
                  <l>nay, thou ſhalt know before thou go, </l>
                  <l>I'le fight before i'le flee:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Again the Shepherd laid on him,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>The Shepherd he begun;</l>
                  <l>hold, hold, cry'd bold <hi>Robin, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>I will yield the wager won:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>With all my heart, ſaid little <hi>Iohn,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>To that I will agree,</l>
                  <l>for he is the flower of Shepherd Swains, </l>
                  <l>The like I did never ſee:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Thus have you heard of <hi>Robin Hood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Alſo of little <hi>Iohn;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ow <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> 
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>hepherd-Swain did conquer them, </l>
                  <l>The like <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> never know:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down, a down, a down, a down.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <pb facs="tcp:35608:40"/>
               <head>Robin Hood's <hi>Golden Prieſts. Shewing how he robbed two Prieſts of Five hundred pound.</hi>
               </head>
               <opener>
                  <hi>Tune is, </hi> Robin Hood <hi>was a tall young-man.</hi>
               </opener>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <hi>I</hi> Have heard talk of bold <hi>Robin hood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And of brave little <hi>Iohn, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Of Fryer <hi>Tuck, </hi> and <hi>Will Scarlet, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Loxſly</hi> and <hi>Maid Marrion,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>hey down, derry derry down.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But ſuch a tale as this before,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>I think there was never known, </l>
                  <l>For <hi>Robin hood</hi> diſguiſed himſelf,</l>
                  <l>and to the Wood he is gone:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>hey down, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Like to a Fryer bold <hi>Robin hood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Was accountred in his array, </l>
                  <l>With Hood, Gown, Beads, and Cru<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>iſi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>,</l>
                  <l>he paſt upon the way,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>hey down, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>He had not gone paſt miles two or three,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:40"/>
                  <l>But it was his chance to ſpy, </l>
                  <l>Two luſty Prieſts clad all in black,</l>
                  <l>come riding gallantly,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>hey down, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Benedicite, then ſaid <hi>Robin hood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Some pitty on me take, </l>
                  <l>Croſs you my hand with a ſilver groat,</l>
                  <l>for our dear Ladies ſake,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>hey down, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>For I have been wandring all this day,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And nothing could I get:</l>
                  <l>Not ſo much as one poor cup of drink,</l>
                  <l>nor bit of bread to eat:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>hey down, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Now by my Holy-dame, the Prieſts reply'd,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>We never a penny have, </l>
                  <l>For we this morning have been rob'd,</l>
                  <l>and could no money ſave:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>hey down, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>I am much afraid, ſaid bold <hi>Robin hood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>That you both do tell a lye, </l>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:41"/>
                  <l>And now before that you go hence,</l>
                  <l>I am reſolved to try:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>hey down, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>When as the Prieſts heard him ſay ſo,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry, derry, down, </hi> 
                  </l>
                  <l>then they rode away amain, </l>
                  <l>But <hi>Robin Hood</hi> betook him to his heels,</l>
                  <l>and ſoon overtook them again:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>hey down, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then <hi>Robin Hood</hi> laid hold on them both,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry, derry, down, </hi> 
                  </l>
                  <l>and pull'd them down from their horſe, </l>
                  <l>O ſpare us Fryer, the Prieſts cry'd out,</l>
                  <l>on us have ſome remorſe:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>hey down, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>You ſaid you had no money, quoth <hi>Robin hood</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry, derry, down, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>wherefore without delay,</l>
                  <l>We three will fall down on our knees,</l>
                  <l>and for money we will pray:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>hey down, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The Prieſts they could not him gain-ſay,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry, derry, down, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>but down they kneel with ſpeed, </l>
                  <l>Send us, O ſend us, then quoth they,
<pb facs="tcp:35608:41"/>
ſome money to ſerve our need:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>hey down, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The Prieſts did pray with a mournful cheer,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry, derry, down, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>ſometimes their hands did wring, </l>
                  <l>Sometimes they wept and cry'd aloud,</l>
                  <l>whilſt <hi>Robin</hi> did merrily ſing:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>hey down, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>When they had been praying an hours ſpace,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry, derry, down, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>the Prieſts did ſtill lament,</l>
                  <l>Then quoth bold <hi>Robin, </hi> now let us ſee,</l>
                  <l>what money heaven hath us ſent:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>hey down, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>We will be ſharers all alike,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry, derry, down, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>of the money that we have, </l>
                  <l>And there is never a one of us,</l>
                  <l>that his fellow ſhall deceive:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>hey down, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The Prieſts their hands in their pockets put,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry, derry, down, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>but money would find none, </l>
                  <l>We'l ſearch our ſelves, ſaid <hi>Robin Hood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l> each other one by one:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>hey down, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:42"/>
                  <l>Then <hi>Robin hood</hi> took pain to ſearch them,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And he found good ſtore of gold:</l>
                  <l>Five hundred pieces preſently upon the graſs he told,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>hey down, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Here is a brave ſhow, ſaid <hi>Robin hood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Such ſtore of gold to ſee, </l>
                  <l>And you each one ſhall have a part,</l>
                  <l>'cauſe you pray'd ſo heartily:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>hey down, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>He gave them fifty pounds a piece,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And the reſt for himſelf did keep, </l>
                  <l>The Prieſts durſt not ſpeak one word,</l>
                  <l>but they ſighed wondrous deep, <hi>hey down, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>With that the Prieſts roſe up from their knees</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry derry down, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Thinking to have parted ſo:</l>
                  <l>Nay ſtay, ſaid <hi>Robin hood,</hi> one thing more</l>
                  <l>I have to ſay e'r you go,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>hey down, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:42"/>
                  <l>You ſhall be ſworn, ſaid bold <hi>Robin hood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry, derry, down, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Vpon this Holy Graſs, </l>
                  <l>That you will never tell lyes again,</l>
                  <l>which way ſoever you paſs,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>hey down, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The ſecond Oath that you here muſt take,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry, derry, down, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>All the days of your lives, </l>
                  <l>You never ſhall tempt Maids to ſin,</l>
                  <l>nor lye with other mens Wives:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>hey down, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The laſt Oath you ſhall take, is this,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry, derry, down, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Be charitable to the poor, </l>
                  <l>Say you have met a Holy Fryer,</l>
                  <l>and I deſire no more:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>hey down, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>He ſet them on their horſes again,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>derry, derry, down, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And away then they did ride, </l>
                  <l>And he return'd to the merry green-wood,</l>
                  <l>with great joy, mirth, and pride:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>hey down, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <pb facs="tcp:35608:43"/>
               <head>Robin Hood's <hi>Chaſe: Or; A merry Progreſs between</hi> Robin Hood <hi>and King</hi> Henry<hi>: ſhewing how</hi> Robin Hood <hi>led the King his Chaſe, from</hi> London <hi>to</hi> Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don; <hi>and when he had taken his leave of the Queen, he return'd to merry</hi> Sherwood.</head>
               <opener>To the Tune of, Robin Hood and the Beggar.</opener>
               <lg>
                  <l>COme you Gallants all, to you I do call,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey down, down a down,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l> that now is within this place, </l>
                  <l>For a Song I will ſing, of <hi>Henry</hi> the King,</l>
                  <l>how he did <hi>Robin hood</hi> chaſe.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Queen <hi>Katherine</hi> ſhe then a match did make,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>as plainly doth appear, </l>
                  <l>For three hundred Tun of good red Wine,</l>
                  <l>and three hundred Tun of Beer.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But yet ſhe had her Archers to ſeek,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>with their Bows and Arrows ſo good, </l>
                  <l>But her mind it was bent, with a good intent,</l>
                  <l>to ſend for bold <hi>Robin hood.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But when bold <hi>Robin hood</hi> he came there,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:43"/>
                  <l>Queen <hi>Katherine</hi> ſhe did ſay, </l>
                  <l>Thou art welcome <hi>Loxſly</hi> ſaid the Queen,</l>
                  <l>and all thy Yeomen gay.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>For a match of ſhooting I have made,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>and thou on my part muſt be, </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Rob.</hi> If I miſs the mark, be it light or dark,</l>
                  <l>then hanged will I be.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But when the Game it came to be played,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>bold <hi>Robin</hi> then drew nigh;</l>
                  <l>With his mantle of green, moſt brave to be ſeen,</l>
                  <l>he let his arrows flye.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>And when the Game it ended was,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>bold <hi>Robin</hi> wan it with grace;</l>
                  <l>But after the King was angry with him,</l>
                  <l>and vowed he would him chaſe.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>What though his pardon granted was,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>while he with them did ſtay, </l>
                  <l>But yet the King was vexed at him,</l>
                  <l>when as he was gone his way.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Soon after the King from the Court did hie,
<pb facs="tcp:35608:44"/>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>in a furious angry mood, </l>
                  <l>And often enquire both far and neer,</l>
                  <l>after bold <hi>Robin Hood.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But when the King to <hi>Nottingham</hi> came,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>bold <hi>Robin</hi> was in the wood;</l>
                  <l>O come ſaid he, and let me ſee,</l>
                  <l>who can find me bold <hi>Robin Hood.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But when bold <hi>Robin Hood</hi> he did hear,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>the King had him in chaſe;</l>
                  <l>Then ſaid little <hi>John</hi> 'tis time to be gone,</l>
                  <l>and go to ſome other place.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then away they went from merry <hi>Sherwood</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi>&amp;c.</l>
                  <l>and into <hi>Yorkſhire</hi> he did hye;</l>
                  <l>And the King did follow with a hoop &amp; a hal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>low,</l>
                  <l>but could not come him nigh.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Yet jolly <hi>Robin</hi> he paſſed along,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>and went ſtraight to <hi>Newcaſtle</hi> town, </l>
                  <l>And there ſtayed he hours two or three,</l>
                  <l>and then he for <hi>Barwick</hi> was gone.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:44"/>
                  <l>When the King he did ſee how <hi>Robin</hi> did flee,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>he was vexed wondrous ſore;</l>
                  <l>With a hoop &amp; a hollow he vowed to follow,</l>
                  <l>and take him or never give o're.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Come now let's away, then cry'd little <hi>John,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>let any man follow that dare, </l>
                  <l>To <hi>Carlile</hi> we'l hye with our company,</l>
                  <l>and ſo then to <hi>Lancaſter.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>From <hi>Lancaſter</hi> then to <hi>Cheſter</hi> they went,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>and ſo did good King <hi>Henry</hi>
                     <hi>:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>But <hi>Robin</hi> away, for he durſt not ſtay,</l>
                  <l>for fear of ſome treachery.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Says <hi>Robin, </hi> come let us to <hi>London</hi> go,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>to ſee our noble Queens face, </l>
                  <l>It may be ſhe wants our company,</l>
                  <l>which makes the King ſo us Chaſe.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>When <hi>Robin</hi> he came Q. <hi>Katherine</hi> before,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>he fell upon his knee, </l>
                  <l>If it pleaſe our Grace, I am come to this place,</l>
                  <l>for to ſpeak with King <hi>Henry.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:45"/>
                  <l>Queen <hi>Katherine</hi> ſhe anſwered bold <hi>Robin</hi> a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gain,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>the King he is gone to merry <hi>Sherwood, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And when he went he to me did ſay,</l>
                  <l>he would go to ſeek <hi>Robin hood.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then fare you well my gracious Queen,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>for to <hi>Sherwood</hi> I will hye apace, </l>
                  <l>For fain would I ſee, what he would with me,</l>
                  <l>if I could but meet with his grace.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But when King <hi>Henry</hi> he came home,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>full weary and vered in mind;</l>
                  <l>And that he did here <hi>Robin</hi> had been there,</l>
                  <l>he blamed Dame fortune unkind.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>You are Welcome home, Queen <hi>Katherine</hi> cry'd,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Henry</hi> my Soveraign Liege:</l>
                  <l>Bold <hi>Robin hood, </hi> that Archer good,</l>
                  <l>your perſon hath been to ſeek.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But when King <hi>Henry</hi> he <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>id hear,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>that <hi>Robin</hi> had been him to ſeek, </l>
                  <l>This anſwer he gave, he's a cunning Knave,</l>
                  <l>for I have ſought him this whole 3 week.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:45"/>
                  <l>A boon, a boon, Queen <hi>Katherine</hi> cry'd,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>I beg it here of your Grace, </l>
                  <l>To pardon his life, and ſeek no more ſtrife,</l>
                  <l>and ſo endeth <hi>Robin Hood</hi>'s Chaſe.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>
                  <hi>Little</hi> Iohn <hi>and the four Beggers. A new merry Song of</hi> Robin Hood, <hi>and little</hi> Iohn; <hi>ſhewing how little</hi> Iohn <hi>went a beg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ging; and how he fought with four Beg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gers, and what a Prize he got from theſe beggers.</hi>
               </head>
               <opener>
                  <hi>To the tune of, </hi> Robin Hood <hi>and the Beggar.</hi>
               </opener>
               <lg>
                  <l>ALL you that delight to ſpend ſome time,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey down, down a down, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>A merry ſong for to ſing, </l>
                  <l>Vnto me draw near, and you ſhall hear,</l>
                  <l>how little <hi>Iohn</hi> went a begging.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>As <hi>Robin hood</hi> walkt the Forreſt along,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>And all his Yeomandree:</l>
                  <l>Says <hi>Robin, </hi> ſome of you muſt a begging go,</l>
                  <l>and little <hi>Iohn</hi> it muſt be thee.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Says <hi>Iohn, </hi> if I muſt a begging go,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>I will have a Palmers Weed, </l>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:46"/>
                  <l>With a ſtaff and a coat, and bags of all ſort,</l>
                  <l>the better then I ſhall ſpeed.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Come give me now a bag for my bread,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>And another for my cheeſe, </l>
                  <l>And one for a penny if I get any,</l>
                  <l>that nothing I may leeſe.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Now little <hi>John</hi> is a begging gone,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>wirh a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Seeking for ſome relief, </l>
                  <l>But of all the Beggers he met on the way,</l>
                  <l>little <hi>Iohn</hi> he was the chief.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But as he was walking himſelf alone,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Four Beggers he chanced to ſpy, </l>
                  <l>Some deaf, and ſome blind, and ſome came behind,</l>
                  <l>ſays <hi>Iohn</hi> here's brave company.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Good morrow (ſaid <hi>Iohn)</hi> my brethren dear,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Good fortune I had you to ſee, </l>
                  <l>Which way do you go? pray let me know,</l>
                  <l>for I want ſome company.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>O what is here to do? then ſaid little <hi>Iohn,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:46"/>
                  <l>Why rings all theſe Bells, ſaid he, </l>
                  <l>what dog is hanging? come let us be ganging</l>
                  <l>that we the truth may ſee.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Here is no dog hanging, one of them ſaid,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Good fellow I tell unto thee, </l>
                  <l>But here is one dead will give us Cheeſe and bread,</l>
                  <l>and it may be one ſingle Penny.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>We have brethren in <hi>London, </hi> another ſaid,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>So have we in <hi>Coventry, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>In <hi>Berwick</hi> and <hi>Dover, </hi> &amp; all the world over,</l>
                  <l>but ne'r a crookt Carl like thee.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Therefore ſtand thee back thou crooked carl,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>And take that knock on the crown, </l>
                  <l>Nay, ſaid little <hi>Iohn, </hi> i'le not yet be gone,</l>
                  <l>for a bout will I have with you round.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Now have at you all, then ſaid little <hi>Iohn,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>If you be ſo full of your blows, </l>
                  <l>Fight on all four, and never give o're,</l>
                  <l>whether you be friends or foes.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Iohn</hi> nipped the dumb, and made him to roar<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                     <pb facs="tcp:35608:47"/>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>And the blind that could not ſee, </l>
                  <l>And he that a Cripple had been ſeven years,</l>
                  <l>he made him run faſter then he.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>And flinging them all againſt the wall,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>With many a ſturdy bang, </l>
                  <l>It made <hi>Iohn</hi> ſing to hear the gold ring,</l>
                  <l>which againſt the walls cry'd twang.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then he got out of the beggers cloak,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Three hundred pound in gold:</l>
                  <l>Good fortune had I, then ſaid little <hi>Iohn,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l> ſuch a good ſight to behold.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But what found be in a Beggars bag,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>But three hundred pound and three?</l>
                  <l>If I drink water while this doth laſt,</l>
                  <l>than an ill death may I dye.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>And my begging trade I will now give o're,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>My fortune it hath been ſo good:</l>
                  <l>Therefore i'le not ſtay, but I will away,</l>
                  <l>to the Forreſt of merry <hi>Sherwood.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:47"/>
                  <l>But when to the Forreſt of <hi>Sherwood</hi> he came</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>He quickly there did ſee, </l>
                  <l>His Maſter good, bold <hi>Robin hood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l> and all his company.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>What news, what news, then ſaid <hi>Robin,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Come little <hi>Iohn</hi> tell unto me, </l>
                  <l>How haſt thou ſped with thy beggers trade?</l>
                  <l>for that I would fain ſee.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>No news but good, ſaid little <hi>Iohn,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>With begging full well I have ſped, </l>
                  <l>Three hundred and three, I have here for thee,</l>
                  <l>in ſilver and gold ſo red.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then <hi>Robin hood</hi> took little <hi>Iohn</hi> by the hand</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>And danced about the Oak-tree, </l>
                  <l>If we drink water whilſt this day doth laſt,</l>
                  <l>then an ill death may we dye.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>So to conclude my merry new ſong,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>with a hey, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>All you that delight to ſing, </l>
                  <l>
                     <g ref="char:punc">▪</g>Tis of <hi>Robin hood</hi> that Archer good,</l>
                  <l>and how little <hi>Iohn</hi> went a begging.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <pb facs="tcp:35608:48"/>
               <head>Robin Hood's <hi>Delight: Or, A merry combat fought between</hi> Ro. Hood, <hi>Little</hi> Iohn, <hi>and</hi> Will. Scaret, <hi>and three ſtout Keepers in</hi> Sherwood <hi>Forreſt.</hi>
               </head>
               <opener>
                  <hi>To the Tune of, </hi> Robin Hood <hi>and Queen</hi> Ka<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>therine: <hi>or, </hi> Robin Hood <hi>and the Shepherd.</hi>
               </opener>
               <lg>
                  <l>THere is ſome will talk of Lords &amp; Kts.</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a down down, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And ſome of Yeomen good, </l>
                  <l>But I will tell you of <hi>Will. Scarlet, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Little <hi>Iohn, </hi> and <hi>Robin Hood.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>They were Out-laws as it is weſt known,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a down down, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And men of a noble blood;</l>
                  <l>And many a time was their valour ſhown, </l>
                  <l>In the Forreſt of merry <hi>Sherwood.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Vpon a time it chanced ſo,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a down down, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>As <hi>Robin</hi> would <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ave it be, </l>
                  <l>They all three would a walking go, </l>
                  <l>Some paſtime for to ſee.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>And as they walkt the Forreſt along,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a down down, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Vpon a Mid-ſummer day.</l>
                  <l>There was he aware of three Forreſters, </l>
                  <l>Clad all in green array.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:48"/>
                  <l>With brave long Fauchions by their ſides,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>And Forreſt-Bills in hand, </l>
                  <l>They call'd aloud to thoſe Out-laws, </l>
                  <l>And charged them to ſtand.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Why who are you, cry'd bold <hi>Robin,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>That ſpeaks ſo boldly here?</l>
                  <l>We three belong to King <hi>Henry, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And are Keepers of his Deer.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The Devil thou art, ſaid <hi>Robin Hood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>I am ſure it is not ſo:</l>
                  <l>We be the Keepers of this Forreſt, </l>
                  <l>And that you ſoon ſhall know.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Your Coats of green lay on the ground,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>And ſo will we all three, </l>
                  <l>And take your ſwords and bucklers<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> round, </l>
                  <l>And try the victory.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>We be content the Keepers ſaid,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>We be three and no leſs, </l>
                  <l>Then why ſhould we of you be afraid, </l>
                  <l>And we never did tranſgreſs.</l>
                  <l>Why, if you be the Keepers in this Forreſt,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:49"/>
                  <l>Then we be three Rangers good, </l>
                  <l>And we'l make you to know before you do go, </l>
                  <l>You met with bold <hi>Robin hood, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>We be content thou bold Out-Law,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Our valour here to try, </l>
                  <l>And will make you know before we go, </l>
                  <l>We will fight before we will flye, &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Then come draw your ſwords, you bold Out-laws,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>And no longer ſtand to prate, </l>
                  <l>But let us try it out with blows, </l>
                  <l>For Cowards we do hate, &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Here is one of us for <hi>Will Scarlet;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>And another for little <hi>Iohn, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And I my ſelf for <hi>Robin hood, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Becauſe he is ſtout and ſtrong, &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>So they fell to it full hard and ſore,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>It was on a Mid-ſummers day, </l>
                  <l>From eight a clock till two and paſt, </l>
                  <l>They all ſhew'd gallant play, &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>There <hi>Robin, </hi> and <hi>Will, </hi> and little <hi>Iohn,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>They fought moſt manfully, </l>
                  <l>Till all their wind was ſpent and gone, </l>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:49"/>
                  <l>Then <hi>Robin</hi> aloud did cry, &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>O hold, O hold, crys bold <hi>Robin,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>I ſee you be ſtout men:</l>
                  <l>Let me blow one blaſt on my beagle-horn, </l>
                  <l>Then I'le fight with you again, &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>That bargain is to make, bold <hi>Robin hood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>Therefore we it deny:</l>
                  <l>Though a blaſt upon thy beagle-horn, </l>
                  <l>Cannot make us fight nor flye, &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Therefore fall on, or elſe be gone,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And yield to <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>s the day, </l>
                  <l>It ſhall never be ſaid that we were afraid</l>
                  <l>Of thee, nor thy Yeamen gay, &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>If that it he ſo, crys bold <hi>Robin,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Let me but know your names, </l>
                  <l>And in the Forreſt of merry <hi>Sherwood, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>I ſhall extol your Fames, &amp;c.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>And with our names, one of them ſaid,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>What haſt thou here to do?</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb facs="tcp:35608:50"/>
                  <l>Except that thou will fight it out, </l>
                  <l>Our names thou ſhalt not know.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>We will fight no more, ſays bold <hi>Robin,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>You be men of valour ſtout, </l>
                  <l>Come and go with me to <hi>Nottingham, </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And there we will fight it out.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>With a Butt of Sack we will bang it out,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>To ſee who wins the day, </l>
                  <l>And for the coſt make you no doubt, </l>
                  <l>I have gold and money to pay.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>And ever hereafter ſo long as we live,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>We all will brethren be, </l>
                  <l>For I love thoſe men with heart and hand, </l>
                  <l>That will fight and never flee.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>So away they went to <hi>Nottingham,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down a, </hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  <l>With Sack <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>o make amends, </l>
                  <l>For three days ſpace they wine did chaſe, </l>
                  <l>And drank themſelves good friends:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>down, a down, a down, a down.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
               <pb facs="tcp:35608:50"/>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
